<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Games Blog Club</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description>The most complete and relevant reviews of games</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 13:06:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logo-150x150.jpg</url>
	<title>Games Blog Club</title>
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Anno 1800 Review – I Burned Another City Down</title>
		<link>./../2019/05/03/anno-1800-review-i-burned-another-city-down/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=120</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>The more cities I build, parks I run and businesses I manage it becomes clearer and clearer that I should never be allowed in a position of power. Somehow my ventures always end up in flames, at least three dead donkeys and half the population having been abducted by aliens. Long story. Still, despite my absolute uselessness at planning a city I still love the city-builder genre. I get an immense sense of pride when I finally get everything running just right. So here we are with Anno 1800, the latest in the long-running series. But does it let me cock things up in new and exciting ways?</p>



<p>Before we go any further, though, you need to know that I’m coming at this from the perspective of an Anno newcomer. I’ve never touched the series before, and thus if you’re a die-hard fan of Anno looking for a detailed comparison between Anno 1800 and its predecessors then this isn’t the review for you. Sorry!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Platforms: PC</p><p>Reviewed On: PC</p><p>Developer: Blue Byte</p><p>Publisher: Ubisoft</p><p>Review code provided by the publisher</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-20-13-42-24.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44360"/></figure>



<p>There’s a lengthy campaign in Anno 1800 that you can easily sink 10-30 hours into, depending on how quickly you blast through the objectives. It follows the story of two siblings whose father was accused of treason and found dead in his cell. Naturally events are not what they initially seem to be and thus begins a tale of family, betrayals and new allies. In the middle of it all you have to set up a whole new island in the name of the Queen, earn favor and try to figure everything out.</p>



<p>The campaign serves as a tutorial of sorts, though it does miss out some key ideas and mechanics. To my surprise I found myself enjoying the simple storyline. Sure, it’s nothing special, has no real characters to speak of and has the worst lip-syncing seen outside of a teenage girl’s Youtube channel, but for a game in this genre it’s surprisingly strong stuff.</p>



<p>At first Anno 1800 feels pretty much like any other city-builder, except it’s gorgeous to look at. A quick zoom in reveals heaps of detail, from people wandering the streets to the hustle and bustle of a marketplace or pub. There’s even a first-person mode that lets you walk around your city, complete with the sound of footsteps. And even if you turn the settings down it still manages to look rather pretty.</p>



<p>Things begin as you might expect; a few houses connected to the Harbor via roads, a logging camp for wood and a timber mill to start pumping out the planks needed for more basic structures. Anno 1800 continues this way, the steady growth of your city bringing with it a need for more complex production chains. To make cannons to produce a ship, for example, you’ll need iron and coal mines where people can slave away in the dark, a furnace to melt the iron down, a steelworks and finally a weapon factory. Each of these have different construction needs, too. Finally, each one produces resources and goods at different rates, so to get the most of your production line you may need to double up on certain buildings. Throughout it all you’ll need to expand your city in order to provide enough people to produce everything.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-23-16-51-17.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44367"/></figure>



<p>Planning everything out can sometimes be fiddly in city-building games, which is why I was delighted by Anno 1800’s blueprint mode which lets you place down as many buildings as you like without committing to them. This lets you design entire cities from the opening minutes of the game. As much as I love this genre my cities often end up being sprawling messes because I’m terrible at planning ahead. I had planned to turn chunks of land into housing but that was forgotten and they got used for other things. Blueprint mode is the perfect answer to this.</p>



<p>In some ways Anno 1800 feels wonderfully streamlined compared to other games in the genre. Unlike Tropico 6 there’s no need to worry about making sure people are close to their jobs, for example, nor do you have to consider public transportation routes. Hell, even unemployment isn’t a major problem. You can have as many excess workers as you like milling around, provided you have means to meet their requirements. Anno 1800 doesn’t try to simulate every individual person in a colony, and instead treats each group of people as a single entity. If you run out of beer then it isn’t just Tom the Baker whose going to be pissed off, it’s going to be <em>everyone</em>.</p>



<p>People are still very much at the centre of the game, though. Things kick off with simple farmers but if their basic needs for fish, schnapps and clothes are met, and they’re happy, then farmer’s residences can be upgraded to workers. These workers bring access to more types of buildings. However, they also have extra needs such as beer and sausages. Meet those needs and you can again upgrade workers to Artisans. And yes, they have more needs too: canned foods, sewing machines and more. The trick is keeping your workforce balanced because you still need farmers to tend crops, workers to forge steel and Artisans to…er, artisan?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-20-14-8-26.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44361"/></figure>



<p>Its by successfully providing basic and luxury goods to your ungrateful flesh-bag citizens that you generate money with which to expand further and further. If your supply of something fails, though, you’ll notice the income dropping faster than a Sumo Wrestler off a cliff. Apparently your citizens are all too happy to leave the city if they aren’t getting enough sausage or if you briefly run out of sewing machines. Ensuring that you’re bolstering your basic infrastructure when adding more housing is key.</p>



<p>But some things can’t be grown or produced locally. Your island might not support the growth of hops, and thus beer has to be bought in from neighbouring islands. This is usually what sparks the urge to settle a new island whereupon it all starts over again. Your treasury is a universal constant but other than that your new island is a separate entity. This is where your forays into setting up trade routes may begin. Ships can be assigned to buy and sell goods with the A.I. characters, but you can also have them ferry goods between your own islands. Before long you’ll have a complex network of shipping routes ferrying rum, fur coats and fancy items across the seas.</p>



<p>Things get more complicated when the game introduces The New World, a separate map with its own islands, a new set of citizen types, buildings and goods to produce. Trade routes can again be set up between this new area and the old, though travel times are much longer. Finally, the rum that your first island wanted can be gotten thanks to the sugar plantations of The New World. Setting all of this up can feel like a real challenge, but once everything is running smoothly there’s a strong sense of pride to be found.</p>



<p>Once the money is flowing you can always look to start grabbing shares in your competition’s islands. Each individual island has five shares and their value is determined by the local economy. Buy a share and you’ll damage diplomatic relationships with the owner, sure, but in return you get an extra chunk of income. Buy all five shares and you can buy the island outright, tossing the opposition to the curb and taking over all the existing infrastructure. In this way you can get rid of pesky A.I. without declaring war. Capitalism, people!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-22-20-6-27.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44365"/></figure>



<p>Speaking of which, building a navy is a big part of the game. We’ve already covered setting up trade routes, but you can also spend time and resources to build frigates, gunboats and massive ships of the line. These are handy for dealing with pirates who may seek to raid your trade vessels. You can also just sell them if you prefer with a ship of the line fetching about $50,000, a good chunk of cash.</p>



<p>I mentioned diplomacy a few paragraphs back so lets talk about that briefly. I say briefly because there’s no much depth to that side of the game. You can compliment A.I. players or give them gifts, or you can insult them or declare war. They’ll also approve of or dislike things you do, so choosing to alter the local newspaper might not go down well with the larger world. If your status is good enough a trade agreement can be reached, opening up more opportunity for turning a profit. And if its really good you can agree upon an alliance.</p>



<p>Somehow there’s even a light loot game jammed into all of this. From ship wreckage, other players and for completing missions you can acquire various bits of gear that can be slotted into special buildings or onto ships. These can bump up productivity or add self repairing to a warship. Gathering up the best stuff is quite satisfying, like you’re a posh collector of fine arts.</p>



<p>These bits of gear include items for your zoo and museum, yet another layer Anno 1800 has. Tourism isn’t as much of a focus as in something like the Tropico series, but you can still build a nice zoo and museum to attract visitors to your islands who will then spend some cash. If you want you can even specialize an island for this by avoiding industrial factories and other eyesores. Sadly positioning housing well away from farms and factories doesn’t seem to have any impact. A factory spewing smoke will have the same negative effect on island beauty wherever it may be.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-22-20-24-48.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44366"/></figure>



<p>And that’s not even mentioning the expeditions that you can send ships on. Occasionally a character will pop up offering new expeditions to acquire zoo animals or relics for your museum or other perhaps even special citizens. To go on an expedition you just have to assign a ship and then watch it sail off into the distance. It’ll probably fail, mind you. You see, on the expedition screen you’ll see things that will most likely be needed on the mission: diplomacy, or firepower, or a high chance of needing to hunt. To help out with this you can equip various bits of gear, plus chuck some food on the boat to help with morale.</p>



<p>Okay, once the ship has been successfully shoved off into the big wide ocean it can be instantly forgotten about. For the most part it requires no oversight. That is, until the captain pops up on your screen with a predicament. Your vessel can come across numerous situations which will appear as chunks of text. Perhaps there are some pirates hunting the ship down, or maybe you’ve encountered a small village or whatever. You’ll be presented with a few choices on how to handle the issue. Depending on your ship and the gear you equipped it with certain choices will have a much higher chance of success. Regardless of how things play out after each event your crew will take a morale hit, simply due to the rigours of the expedition. If morale hits zero bad things will happen, so sending the ship home is always an option. But you can also use rations from the ship to massively reduce the morale hit.</p>



<p>Aside from an example in the campaign these expeditions are entirely optional pieces of Anno 1800. It’s an extra layer of gameplay that fits neatly within everything else yet never needs to be touched if you’d rather focus on building your islands up.</p>



<p>Speaking of optional stuff, you can pick up various quests along the way. A.I. players will occasionally offer you missions to escort their ships or deliver a crap-load of a specific resource like sails. Doing these typically nets you some extra cash, plus it’ll improve your relationship with the quest giver. Meanwhile, in settlements your people will occasionally ask for things like taking a picture of a wedding or finding five random alligators that are roaming the streets. Yes, that’s an actual thing that pops up.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anno-18002019-4-22-17-14-27.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44364"/></figure>



<p>Sadly the quests are one of Anno 1800’s weaker elements. An escort mission means nothing more than assigning a ship or two to the vessel needing protection and then forgetting about it. Finding five random alligators or some woman’s husband is no more exciting than scanning the streets then clicking on a few things. Meanwhile, the constant needs and demands of running multiple cities continue to churn away in the background while you stare at a street because you can’t find that lost sodding alligator.</p>



<p>The biggest flaw within Anno 1800 is one that the developers are already working on. On the whole the game is a bit crap at giving you the information you need to solve problems. A glance at a warehouse, for example, will let you see whether a particular item is stable, decreasing or increasing. That’s fine if all you need is to know if you outputting enough beer, but for setting up trade routes it’s incredibly vague. How much beer can I export? I have no idea because I don’t know how much excess I’m producing nor the amount my city actually needs. Likewise, if you upgrade a few buildings you can suddenly find income dropping like a stone because now Schnapps production isn’t high enough. Again, there’s no way to figure that out beforehand and have the right infrastructure in place.</p>



<p>Still, while the lack of detailed information did lead to a few crazy moments where my entire economy suddenly collapsed like a tower of cards that had been piece together by the local drunk, for the most part I was able to work around it and enjoy Anno 1800 thoroughly. Indeed, I might put this up there with the likes of Cities Skylines as one of the best city-builders around. It really is that good, even if it doesn’t do anything particularly new or ground-breaking. I was invested in planning out my islands, in setting up lucrative trade routes and buying up competitor’s shares. I really, really love this freaking game and I can’t wait to see where it goes from here.<br></p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>World War Z Review – The New Left 4 Dead?</title>
		<link>./../2019/05/03/world-war-z-review-the-new-left-4-dead/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 08:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=117</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>Considering that World War Z, the film starring Brad Pitt based on the book that didn’t star Brad Pitt, came out waaaaay back in 2013 it seems a tad odd to release an official World War Z videogame some six years later. And yet here we are. But despite being based upon the movie World War Z is much more like a sequel to Left 4 Dead 2 in spirit, if not in name. Also, this doesn’t star Brad Pitt, either.</p>



<p>Instead of one big narrative that perhaps acts as a sequel to the movie there are basically four mini-campaigns spread across four different regions: New York, Jeurselum, Moscow and Japan. And each of those gets 3 small missions. In a nice touch each of the four locations has its own band of playable characters, so you’re basically following four short tales of survivors attempting to escape, rescue somebody or both. But ultimately these characters are forgettable and the stories are as strong as wet paper. A few cutscenes attempt to justify what you’re doing, but you’ll have forgotten them as soon as they’ve finished.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Platforms: Xbox One, PS4 &amp; PC</p><p>Reviewed On: Xbox One</p><p>Developer: Saber Interactive</p><p>Publisher: Saber Interactive</p><p>Review code provided by the publisher</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/World_War_Z_Screenshot_02.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44339"/></figure>



<p>But let’s be honest, none of us are here for the story. Nah, we’re here for the zombies and the shooting of said zombies. Right, so here’s the basics; you and three other players will team up to run through levels while picking up weapons and gunning down hundreds of zombies. There’s not a lot to actually talk about when it comes to these core mechanics; the 3rd person combat is fine, though the guns feel a little weedy. Zombies can be mown down with ease, especially if you nail those headshots, and they can even get their arms and legs blown, shot or chopped off.</p>



<p>What sets this apart from its obvious Left 4 Dead inspiration are the six classes that you can choose from. Every class has about 30 different perks to purchase. My preference was the medic because many of the perks are geared toward helping others to benefit yourself. One perk, for example, makes it so that using a med-kit on another player heals me for 50% as well. You can take one perk from each column, totalling 6 perks. This gives plenty of room for specializing your build.</p>



<p>In terms of shooty stuff there’s a pretty standard selection of weapons. Assault rifles, shotguns, SMGs and more are strewn around the levels just waiting to be picked up and put to good use. As you use them you’ll unlock more powerful versions that can be bought using the supplies you earn after each mission. Combined with purchasing perks there’s a lot to unlock and play with, provided that you’re willing to grind a bit to get it all.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/World_War_Z_Screenshot_01.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44338"/></figure>



<p>This is absolutely meant to be played with friends, but you can also play with A.I. in case you want to avoid humans entirely or with a mixture of people and A.I. These artificial players are something of a mixed bag, being surprisingly helpful when it comes to gunning down zombies and picking you up when you’re downed. However, when it comes to their fellow A.I. they are strangely uncaring and will happily watch on as an A.I. is brutally massacred in front of them. It’s frankly a little creepy. I mean, I’ve seen A.I. being mauled to death by a Lurker while his comrade watches on, almost like there’s some sort of dark, personal history between the two of them.</p>



<p>In other words, while the A.I. works and is fun to play with this is a much stronger game when played with friends or random players. For this reason I appreciate that the developers did include a few tricks to help people who don’t play with a mic. You can drop markers on the map and even highlight weapons or equipment pickups, as well as point out specific enemies. Good stuff.</p>



<p>What isn’t so good is trying to heal other players. There’s a notable delay between looking at another player and the option to heal them popping up, and in that time they’ve usually run off. To be fair, if you have a mic you can simply tell them to stop being a stupid bitch and stand still, but quite a few times I went in without a mic and wound up in absurd chases around the map trying to heal players.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/World_War_Z_Screenshot_07.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44342"/></figure>



<p>I did appreciate that stealth is an option, too. Typically, you start off with a silenced pistol, but other quiet weapons are available. Providing you nail head shots or take a zombie down quickly then nearby undead will ignore you. With some careful teamwork you can work through whole chunks of levels without having to deal with rampaging hordes of zombies. Of course, when playing with random people things tend to be more…er, chaotic.<br></p>



<p>Individually zombies are about as threatening as a pissed off bunny rabbit. But as a horde they are much more formidable. This is where World War Z excels; zombie hordes include hundreds of corpses and they flow across the landscape like a decaying tidal wave of flesh. It’s a cool sight to behold, and just like in the movie the zombies will form pyramids out of themselves in order to get up to high areas. Unload a couple of magazines into the unfortunate zombies stuck at the bottom of the pyramid and you can bring the whole thing crashing down like a crappy cheerleading team. Facing off against the mega-hordes of putrid undead is a great moment that never actually got old. Everytime I saw them gushing out of pipes and pouring over fences it brought a grin to my face.</p>



<p>A few times throughout a level you’ll be informed that a massive swarm is on its way. With about 90 seconds on the clock your team have a chance to gather up and deploy electrified fences, heavy machine guns and autoturrets. I love these moments where everyone frantically grabs when they can, snatches up some ammo and then turns to look at the horizon, just waiting for inevitable wave of putrifying corpses to come crashing down. On the harder difficulties it takes genuine skill and teamwork to come through unscathed.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/World_War_Z_Screenshot_06.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44341"/></figure>



<p>over the years we’ve seen so many interesting types of zombie in video games to battle. It’s a little frustrating, then, that World War Z has just four distinct zombies outside of the standard shambling variety. There’s the bull who simply charges in to grab a player; the gasbag who explodes into a cloud of poisonous gas upon death; the screamer that will alert endless hordes of zombies until gunned down; and finally the lurker who loves to hide around corners and leap on unsuspecting players. Comparitvely speaking Left 4 Dead 2, which launched in 2009, has eight special zombie types.</p>



<p>Perhaps worse is that you’ll fight against all of those zombies in the first 30-60 minutes of the game. In fact, you’ll have experienced everything the game has to offer within that time frame. There are no new zombies to encounter, no gameplay twists along the way. Nothing. And while the levels may look visually different they have nothing else to set themselves apart. One level plays exactly like the next, though there are a couple of fun set-piece moments like running up a staircase while zombies rain down from above.</p>



<p>Replay value suffers because of this, too. You’ll blitz through the campaign in a couple of hours and the idea is to play through it again and again. But whereas Left 4 Dead 2 had a special A.I. designed to alter enemy and item spawns based on team performance, World War Z has nothing like that. Or at least, if it does I haven’t noticed it. Every level will play out mostly the same as it did before.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/World_War_Z_Screenshot_05.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44340"/></figure>



<p>BUT! Here’s the important bit: this is a budget title, clearly made without massive backing and it’s being sold at a budget price of just $40. The clear limitations are much easier to overlook when you aren’t having to break the bank account to buy the game. So far it seems World War Z has sold pretty well, shifting over a million copies, and that opens the way for DLC and updates which expand the amount of content on offer.</p>



<p>Plus, you’ve got the much more challenging difficulty levels to tackle which ramp up the zombie threat by whole hell of a lot. Defence sections become desperate battles to hold on, team-mates get pinned under a mass of seething bodies and it’s just a much more fun and engaging game overall.</p>



<p>If you get bored with fending off tides of undead with a few other players there’s also a competitive multiplayer on offer. Two teams of four players each face off across a couple of standard game modes. It’d be nothing more than a small distraction if it wasn’t for the fact that zombies are thrown into the mix. Suddenly the choice of whether to hold an objective point or not becomes much more interesting when a horde of undead are inbound. The core combat is nothing special and certainly wouldn’t hold up to much if it was purely player vs player, but with zombies mixed into the action you might actually find yourself sinking a chunk of time into it.</p>



<p>In many ways I could argue that World War Z isn’t a very good game. The combat is nothing exciting, there’s not much content, there’s very little story and it features one of the most overused enemies outside of Nazis. But there’s a fun simplicity to the action, like sitting back with a bucket of popcorn and enjoying a B-grade zombie flick. Mowing down an impressively vast horde of undead is cathartic. I’ve found myself with the urge to go and play a match or two each day.</p>



<p>If you’re looking for a co-op game with a Left 4 Dead flavor then I’d recommend Warhammer: Vermintide 2 first and foremost. But if you absolutely must have zombies and guns then World War Z is surprisingly entertaining stuff that might fill the void that has yet to be filled by Left 4 Dead 3. Maybe. Standing your ground against a tidal wave of corpses is thrilling stuff.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Close to the Sun Review – Not Close Enough</title>
		<link>./../2019/05/03/close-to-the-sun-review-not-close-enough/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=114</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>Close to the Sun likes to label each of its chapters based on Greek mythology, mentioning characters like Icarus. So let me get a bit posh here and chat about Icarus, too. You’ve probably heard the story: Icarus is the son of Daedalus, the designer of the famous Labyrinth where the Minotaur dwelt. The tale goes that Minos imprisoned Daedalus and Icarus in a tower to keep the secret of the maze safe. The two prisoners used feathers and wax to create wings, and leapt from the tower. Daedalus told his son not to fly too high or else the sun would melt the wax holding his wings together, and not to fly too low which would wet the feathers. But because Icarus was a fucking moron he flew too Close to the Sun (HA!) and his wings melted, thus he fell into the sea and drowned. The end. Close to the Sun tries to fly up to the narrative heights of brilliance but its wings start to melt. So it tries to fly down to the cold depths of horror and nearly drowns. And so Close to the Sun never does find its balance. It never soars high in the sky, nor skims the waves. Jesus, this has turned too philosophical. I need a beer or something. Let’s just review this thing, yeah?<br></p>



<p>Although the developers have clearly said that this isn’t the case it’s hard not to see BioShock in Close to the Sun. Whereas Andrew Ryan decided to build an underwater city where the elite would be free to do elite stuff, in Close to the Sun Nicola Tesla opted to construct the Helios, a massive ship to house the world’s greatest minds who could work toward bettering humanity. Entering the Helios evokes some of the same feelings from BioShock, the art style and architecture of the Helios immediately triggering memories of the art-deco style of the underwater city.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Platforms: Xbox One, PS4, PC</p><p>Reviewed On: PC</p><p>Developer: Storm in a Teacup</p><p>Publisher: Wired Productions</p><p>Review code provided by the publisher.</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/close-to-the-sun-Helios-entry-1024x429.png?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44407"/></figure>



<p>Nicola Tesla is one hell of a historical figure, his tale filled with intrigue and mystery at almost every point. In reality, he was unable to pay the mortgage on his Wardenclyffe laboratory and it was demolished before it was even finished. His ideas about wirelessly transmitting power across the globe would never come to fruition, his contributions to science and technology greatly overlooked. In Close to the Sun’s timeline Nicola Tesla has become the richest man in the world, his Wardenclyffe company supplying electricity to half the globe. With his riches Tesla constructed the Helios where the greatest minds could be free of limitations. This hasn’t exactly gone well with the rest of the world, with newspaper headlines claiming that the Helios has been hunted by military vessels.</p>



<p>This is a video game involving science so naturally things go horribly wrong aboard the Helios. Main character Rose Archer (journalist extraordinaire, at least so we are told) gets a letter from her nerdy sister asking her to come aboard the Helios to catch up, but once Rose arrives its clear that things have gone well and truly fucking downhill on the absurdly vast ship. Blood covers the floors, there are bodies everywhere, writing on the walls and some nutcase is wandering around with a knife and mumbling to himself. It’s just another typical day in the life of a video game protagonist.</p>



<p>Except that unlike most first-person games and indeed unlike Bioshock you don’t get any weapons in Close to the Sun. Rose has no means of fighting back against the dangers aboard the Helios. Not even a good old kick to the head or bitch slap.</p>



<p>Most of the interaction between the small cast is handled via radio communication. The relationship between Rose and her sister Ada is great, and I found myself wishing that they got to share a lot more dialogue. Instead, the most conversation occurs between Rose and Aubrey, a man trapped in a section of Helios with the body of his dead best mate who needs help to escape. As enjoyable as the relationship between Rose and Ada is, Aubrey is without a doubt the stand-out character in the game. He’s fantastically voiced and even brings a couple of darkly funny moments. My personal favourite was came when he was asked if he was okay. In a pitch-perfect tone Aubrey replies, “I’m using the dismembered arm of my best friend as a back scratcher, of course I’m not okay.” Great stuff.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/close-to-the-sun-tesla-coil.png?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44410"/></figure>



<p>Close to the Sun absolutely nails its atmosphere. There’s a strong horror element to the game, and the developers spend a long time building up the tension through environmental storytelling. Created on the Unreal Engine Close to the Sun looks absolutely stellar, delivering loads of detail and some great lighting. There were plenty of moments where I stopped and just soaked in the world that Storm in a Teacup have conjured up. The only hiccups in the graphics are the rare occasions when a living human shows up. Character models look…er, weird. The proportions are a little off, the animation is clumsy. It doesn’t look right. But otherwise Close to the Sun looks superb.</p>



<p>Mind you, that does come at a cost. Close to the Sun is a tricky game to run. With my Ryzen 1600 CPU, 16GB of RAM and GTX 1080 Ti I was struggling to hold steady frame rates at 1440p. At times 60 FPS wasn’t a problem, but during certain sections that would drop, sometimes hitting as low as 15 FPS. Thankfully for the most part this isn’t a game that needs fast reflexes, so lower framerates are not as big a problem as they could be. Still, I’d like to see some updates to smooth performance out a bit.</p>



<p>Be warned; there are a lot of jump scares in Close to the Sun. Now, there’s nothing wrong with jump scares when they’re used sparingly, but for my tastes they do get overused here. There are even spots that have a few jump scares in quick succession.</p>



<p>Sadly I think the game struggles to hold on to the tense atmosphere that it so wonderfully weaves within the first hour or two of the 5-8 hour journey. That’s mainly because the realization that there is no danger outside of the pre-defined chase sequences hits you. The creepy noises, strange shadows and jump scares become less effective when you know that almost all of them lead to nothing. And that’s all Close to the Sun has in its arsenal: jump scares and chase sequences. It’s limited in its horror vocabulary.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/close-to-the-sun-massacre.png?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44409"/></figure>



<p>Speaking of the chase sequences, they don’t really evoke terror as they probably should. But the big issue with them is that when it comes to obstacles the game asks you to click on the icon. However, during chases I found these were frequently unresponsive and a few times I was caught and killed due to them. Other than that, provided you don’t make any genuinely stupid mistakes – like running head first into a wall – you’ll always be safe. This also resulted in another unfortunate side effect: I used the look back button more often and thus wound up laughing at the clumsy animations.</p>



<p>The other area where the game’s horror falters like an elderly grandmother that’s been in the pub all day are the bodies. In the first couple of horrors discovering the gruesome corpses add to the air of tension, but eventually there are just so damn many bodies that it becomes kind of funny. They’re everywhere. At some points I struggled to move through bits of the level because Rose won’t step over corpses and instead bumps into an invisible wall. This game has a body county that would impress bloody Game of Thrones.</p>



<p>To describe Close to the Sun as a game that falls into the walking simulator genre almost feels unfair, but it’s also true. A lot of your time will be spent exploring the Helios at a slow pace. Even Rose’s “sprint” is more like the gentle forward stumble of people who feel like they need to jog but don’t actually want to. Strewn around are newspapers, memos, notes, letters and pictures that you can pick up and examine to help flesh out the story a little more. It’s all about soaking in the world that the developers have made.</p>



<p>There are some simple puzzles tossed into the mix, though. Some levers must be flipped, or codes entered into doors. Considering Rose is supposed to be an incredibly good journalist, though, and thus is presumably quite intelligent, Close to the Sun never taxes the mind.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Close-to-the-sun-hall.png?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44406"/></figure>



<p>I enjoyed the journey that Close to the Sun took me on. I like the characters, loved the Helios and was intrigued by the plot. Sadly the end of that journey leaves a sour taste in the mouth. The game sets up numerous questions and plot points but chooses to resolve none of them, abandoning the narrative so that everything can be wrapped up in either DLC or a sequel. Trying to make a story while keeping enough mystery for a follow-up is no easy thing, but Storm in a Teacup failed almost entirely in its attempt. After teasing out story elements and slowly building the mystery up to have almost nothing answered is a real blow. Still, I’d be happy if a sequel was revealed to be in the works. Less so if DLC is announced, simply because then Close to the Sun would be left to feel like an incomplete game, a story that had its ending ripped away in order to be sold separately.<br></p>



<p>This might seem like a short review – and you’d be right, it is – but that’s because there isn’t a lot that can be said about Close to the Sun. From a gameplay perspective there’s not much to break down, and I can’t talk much about the story without spoiling the entire game. Although the chase sequences, light puzzling and ending all fell flat for me I still loved the idea of Close to the Sun. I loved Helios as a setting. I loved the story and the characters. I loved just soaking up the atmosphere. So, taking everything into account I think (emphasis on think) that the score is fair.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trials Rising Review – On Trial For Loot Boxes</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/26/trials-rising-review-on-trial-for-loot-boxes/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 08:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=110</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>Reflecting on yet another failed attempt at an extreme track in Trials Rising at some ungodly hour in the morning, I come to the conclusion that this series has probably evoked more emotional responses out of me than the majority of story-driven games. This is literally a game about riding a bike from one end of a track to the end without falling off too many times. Somehow, though, it can make me laugh, smile, yell, get angry and threaten to murder my friends. I didn’t murder them, though. Honest. It was just heat of the moment. Now hand me a shovel, would you?</p>



<p>Before I delve into the review proper, though, I’d like to take a minute to chat about my relationship with Trials. Way back in the dark ages of time I picked up a serious infection related to my Cystic Fibrosis, and because of that I was placed on intravenous antibiotics. My mum learned how to perform the procedure so that I could go home, but the whole thing was a nightmare because my veins kept collapsing, so I had to go into hospital at 2am and daft stuff like that. Anyway, when I was getting the meds injected it was a painful experience – like a burning sensation travelling up my arm – so to distract me my older brother introduced me to Trials 2. I could play it with one hand, and to be good at it required concentration which in turn kept me from focusing on the feeling of the drugs running up my arm. From then on, Trials became a staple in my life, each new iteration resulting in hundreds of hours of playtime.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Platforms: PC, Xbox One (reviewed) PS4</p><p>Developer: RedLynx</p><p>Publisher: Ubisoft</p><p>Singleplayer: Yes</p><p>Multiplayer: Yes</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/TRIALS_screen_Hot_springs_SP_180821_930am_CET_1534774145.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43537"/></figure>



<p>So, let’s chat about this newest game in the franchise and what it does right, and what it does wrong because there’s quite a bit of both.</p>



<p>The very core of what makes each Trials game brilliant is intact and has barely been touched. I am, of course, talking about the physics that dictate your goal of getting from point A to point B as quickly as you can. Things start off easily enough with fast, flowing tracks that don’t demand too much skill in the use of throttle, brakes and leaning. But it doesn’t take long before the swearing begins as things become trickier and trickier. You’ll need to learn to bunnyhop, stop on a dime, balance on one wheel, use the momentum from a drop to bounce forward and so much more.</p>



<p>The controls are precise, the physics solid and thus the game never feels unfair. Every mistake is yours and yours alone, and every new obstacle overcome is yours to appreciate. Like the games before Trials Rising is easy to learn and impossible to ever truly master.</p>



<p>Once you start moving onto the hard and extreme tracks the tricks and techniques needed can be hard to learn and for many people that created a barrier they struggled to break through. For Trials Rising the guys and gals over at RedLynx have sought to remedy this with an impressive and extensive tutorial. As you progress through the game new sections of the tutorial will open up and teach you the tricky techniques needed. Most importantly the tutorial is entirely optional, so veterans can ignore it and newcomers who want the harder Trials experience can too.</p>



<p>Like in Trials Fusion when you fire up a track you’ll end up racing against ghostly riders. However, whereas Fusion always raided your friends list first, Rising seems to veer more toward picking out random players from around the world. This has the effect of making things feel less personal; where’s the satisfaction in beating xxxSn!p3RxxxxxxxxxYourMumxxxxxx who you have never met? The victory screen after each course is meaningless when maybe only one friend is there, and only wind up serving to make the time between finishing a track and getting to the next one longer.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Trials_Rising_screen_China_E3_110618_230pm_1528734297.jpg?resize=1024%2C570&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43546"/></figure>



<p>Ditching the sci-fi theme of Trials Fusion (and the clever narrative) this latest game goes for a modern-day approach with quite a few tracks focusing on real-world landmarks. The course design here continues to be superb, from the initially flowing easy and medium levels to the much more trials-y tracks that come later. They all present their own challenges, sometimes have fun little gimmicks and typically sport alternate routes that could speed you up. They are a joy to complete.</p>



<p>RedLynx have also stepped up their game when it comes to dressing those courses up. Although it’s hard to admire them when you’re focusing on stopping on a dime there are some awesome set-pieces in the background, many of which play into the track itself like stuff blowing up or moving. There’s even people at track-side now, which if memory serves is a first for the series. From a technical perspective there hasn’t been much of an upgrade here, but there’s so much going on in the background and nice little details that it’s hard to compare.</p>



<p>If there’s any complaint that could be made it’s that Trials Rising doesn’t exactly improve the core formula in any way. The jumps, bumps, loops, leaps and drops are all familiar stuff, so it’s mostly just scenery that’s changed. Considering how many happy hours I’ve already sunk into precariously balancing bikes on various objects, though, that isn’t an issue in my eyes.</p>



<p>There was an attempt to mix things up in Trials Fusion with the introduction of a trick system, but it didn’t prove popular and it has been removed entirely from Rising.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/TRIALS_screen_Eiffel_tower_tandem_180821_930am_CET_1534774161.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43535"/></figure>



<p>However, we do get a fresh, new feature in the form of the tandem bike where two players have to ride a single machine. Each player controls about 50% of the throttle and braking, and its about the same with the leaning. Due to potential lag online the tandem bike is restricted purely to local co-op, but that’s a good thing because it’s absolutely something best experienced with somebody sitting beside you. Playing through a single track is a mixture of swearing, laughing, arguing, giggling and moments of perfect synchronization.</p>



<p>Previously in the series unlocking new tracks was simply a case of getting a bronze medal on the existing ones. It was straightforward and gave the game’s a good sense of momentum. Now, though, things have been changed so that unlocking new stuff is tied to your level.&nbsp;Unfortunately&nbsp;these can result in long periods of having to grind away, the later content locked up behind a gate which demands the sacrifice of time. Lots of bloody time.</p>



<p>To grind your way toward unlocking the new tracks and locations you’ll need to replay prior events and make use of the new contract system. Basically, tracks will now feature a randomly generated challenge from sponsors that offers up stickers or sometimes items of clothing, some currency and a bunch of XP. These range in difficulty but will often challenge you to do something like perform 15 backflips, wheelie 20m and catch up with the ghost of X player.</p>



<p>The issue here is that the contracts&nbsp;fundamentally&nbsp;go against what the Trials series is about. Instead of being as fast, smooth and safe as you can the contracts make it about doing backflips and other stuff. They can be fun from time to time and challenging, but having to grind through them over and over again to unlock the next batch of tracks is a horribly artificial way of increasing the longevity of the game. Trials players already go back and replay tracks to improve their times. There was never a need to force them to do it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Trials_Rising_screen_UKUPMP_E3_110618_230pm_1528734306.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43552"/></figure>



<p>A large part of the reason behind these contracts and levelling up is the inclusion of bloody loot crates. You get one every time you level up, and within them you’ll find three items of varying rarity. These items are utterly dull fare, offering up some basic clothing and piles upon piles of stickers that can be plastered on your bike and rider. It’s an uninspiring loot system that nobody ever asked for, and on top of that duplicates items pop up constantly. It would have been far better had gear been unlocked by doing the contracts instead, at least that way you could potentially chase stuff that you actually wanted.</p>



<p>There is at least an option to buy whatever items you might want using the in-game currency. Cash gets handed out quite slowly, but provided you don’t want to purchase everything in sight you’ll be able to grab what you like.</p>



<p>However, because this is Ubisoft we’re chatting about it’s also possible to spend real money on stuff. Thankfully you can completely ignore the microtransactions and the loot crates themselves if you so choose, but as always it’s disappointing to see this stuff get crammed into yet another game.</p>



<p>Going back to progression for a moment, there’s a new world map that winds up being a pain in the backside. Before long its littered with icons that make finding specific tracks and events much harder than it needs to be. It’s just one more thing that slows the pace of the whole game down.</p>



<p>You can still head online to challenge other people in races where you each get a lane to ride in, or you can do the same thing offline with a few controllers and a couple of willing victims. Trials Rising continues the franchise’s legacy of being a fantastic local multiplayer game. With a group of friends and maybe a few beers and you have yourself a damn good night.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/TRIALS_screen_8Lane_MP_2_180821_930am_CET_1534774129-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43543"/></figure>



<p>The chunky, somewhat daunting track editor returns, too, giving players the opportunity to craft fantastic new stages for the community. It’s a strong toolset that rewards patience and time with the ability to cobble together spectacular stuff. There’s already some jaw-dropping creations available to download and I can’t wait to see what else the talented community of Trials players can come up with.</p>



<p>So let’s wrap all this up, shall we?<br></p>



<p>The issue here is that Trials Rising fundamentally fails to understand what people, myself included, love and adore about the series. What has always been great about Trials is how simple, straightforward and streamlined the games have been; instant respawns when you fail, short loading times, minimal faffing around and bite-sized tracks combined to create something wonderfully pure. I played and still play Trials for the reward of playing Trials and getting better at Trials. Rising messes with this purity, introducing a raft of stuff that only serves to slow the game down. You click on a track and then have to view a sponsor screen. Complete the race and you have to deal with the pointless victory screen, then yet another screen where you’re awarded with XP and coins and tat. It doesn’t sound like much, but in a franchise where there was often just seconds between events it feels like somebody suddenly dumped a vat of raw time into the mix.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Trials_Rising_screen_SkyscraperConstruction_E3_110618_230pm_1528734305.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43551"/></figure>



<p>And what point did somebody say during the development of Trials: Rising that the game needed loot crates? I hope it wasn’t RedLynx themselves because they should damn well know better. I can only assume it was a Ubisoft directive, as were the microtransactions. Look, just fuck off with your loot crates. Then fuck off some more. And when you’ve fucked off some more, fuck off again. Keeping fucking off until you’ve circled the globe and arrived back at my doorstep where you will politely ring my doorbell so I can come and tell you to fuck off again.</p>



<p>Rant&nbsp;done.<br><br>Trials: Rising is a tricky one to score. At its very core what makes the Trials games so addictive, so satisfying and so god-damn rewarding is still present. Once again I found myself clutching the controller at 3am with a slightly manic expression plastered across my sweat-covered face, mumbling something about needing to bounce the back wheel off that edge to shave off some time. Once again, I found myself thinking, “Just one more go. Alright, maybe two.” again and again and again. It’s just irritating that Trials, arguably the quintessential example of a sleek game, has got bloated in this latest iteration.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anthem Review – Not my Jam</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/26/anthem-review-not-my-jam/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 08:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=107</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>BioWare’s career has been filled with incredible games, from Star Wars: Knights of the old Republic to the Mass Effect trilogy and Dragon Age. For many, myself included, the company has a special place in our hearts. Yet things have been rough for BioWare of late, with Mass Effect: Andromeda falling flat on its oddly animated face. Now, we have Anthem, a new live-service, co-op looter-shooter in the vein of Destiny and The Division that has been in development for nearly seven years. After spending dozens and dozens of hours in Anthem, though, I can’t help but wonder what the hell happened in those seven years.</p>



<p>The answer, I suspect, is somewhere along the line Anthem was mostly scrapped and then rebuilt, because it’s hard to see how seven years of development time could have produced something so clumsy, messy and lacking in content. There’s good to be found in Anthem and plenty of potential for the future, but if you were looking forward to seeing what seven years of pure BioWare work could produce then you’re going to be left unhappy.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Platforms: PC, Xbox One (tested) &amp; PS4</p><p>Developer: BioWare</p><p>Publisher: EA</p><p>Singleplayer: Yes</p><p>Multiplayer: Yes</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-part2-screenshot-03-final-16x9-wm.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43618"/></figure>



<p>So buckle in boys and girls, because this is going to be a long, rambling review. I’ve read the work of the likes of Eurogamer and Rockpapershotgun who managed to somehow describe and review Anthem in condensed fashion. Me, though? I’m going with a word vomit of a review complete with chunks of suspicious vegetables and carrots that I’m sure I never ate. Let’s do this.<br></p>



<p>Anthem makes a good first impression thanks to its freaking gorgeous visuals. The world of Bastion should be a paradise for its people, the lush jungles and numerous waterfalls creating a feast for the ‘ol eyeballs, but since this is a video game pretty much everything in Bastion wants to kill you. There is plenty of savage wildlife looking for a meal, as well as the Scar ( a strange race of bugs, apparently) and the Dominion. But it’s easy to forget about all that violent death stuff when you’re busy flying through a natural rock archway or standing atop a cliff just soaking up the view.</p>



<p><br>The world of Anthem is a fairly fascinating one, awash with backstory and plenty of gibberish words that you’ll likely frown at. The general gist is that there was once a race known as the Shapers who sought to harness the mysterious Anthem (which some people can hear) in combination with their machines to reshape the world. However, the Shapers are long gone, and now their technology and the Anthem runs roughshod on the world, with ancient relics constantly spawning monsters, swapping the gravity around, creating storms and much more.</p>



<p>As a Freelancer you have access to a Javelin, a suit of mechanized armour that links to the wearer. Backing up each Freelancer is a Cypher, someone with vaguely defined mental abilities that allow them to process an insane amount of information so that they can support Freelancers out in the field. So what do Freelancers actually do? Well, technically they do pretty much anything as almost anyone can hire a Freelancer to do a contract. Freelanders, though, do specialize in “silencing” shaper relics, going into dangerous situations in order to hopefully make them a tad less dangerous. In the time the game takes place the reputation of the Freelancers isn’t as good as it once was, they are no longer viewed as the heroes they once were.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthemstorm.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43614"/></figure>



<p>There’s a lot going on in Anthem’s world, which in turn gives BioWare a healthy foundation to build on. Be prepared to do some reading, however, because like the Mass Effect franchise BioWare have hidden a lot of the lore away in menus. Unlike Mass Effect, though, Anthem doesn’t always provide enough information upfront to properly contextualize things in the story, so if you never venture into the Cortex a lot of story aspects, concepts and lingo will be left vague and fuzzy.</p>



<p>As for the story, things kick off with your nameless (but voiced) Freelancer entering the Heart of Rage along with a team. Things go badly, people get killed and ultimately the Heart of Rage lives on, a storm ravaging the land. The story skips two years ahead to where a bad guy going by The Monitor has decided to do some evil stuff for some evil reasons. You need to get the band back together, kill the bad guy, save the day and maybe get a few cool new guns in the process.</p>



<p>The overarching story is ultimately kind of naff. Mostly that’s because The Monitor is a boring bad guy who barely even appears in the story. While it’s nice that he speaks calmly rather than yelling – having presumably gone to the Thanos school of bad guying – he remains completely undeveloped.</p>



<p>As for the rest of the story it’s largely forgettable stuff that never makes use of the deep intriguing world BioWare have made. What saves the plot are the characters who are almost all likeable and well acted. There are three truly core people: Own is your Cypher and an enthusiastic lad with designs toward becoming a Freelancer in his own right: Haluk was one the best Freelancer around and holds a grudge against you for pulling him out of the Heart of Rage; and finally there’s Faye, your old Cypher who heard the Anthem while in the Heart of Rage. Much of the story revolves around Haluk, Faye and your own character rebuilding their relationship after it felt apart due to the events in the Heart of Rage.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-vga-07.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43613"/></figure>



<p>You’ll never connect as deeply with this small cast as you did with Mass Effect’s roster of brilliant personalities, but they’re still a nice bunch and I found myself looking forward to conversations with them. It’s just a shame that they never accompany you on missions or anything like that, which would have helped make a connection to them.</p>



<p>Fort Tarsis acts as a hub that you head back to between missions, whereupon the game swaps from 3rd person to 1st. There are a bunch of other NPCs to chat to, and they all have their own little stories to tell over time. Again, the acting tends to be quite strong, even if the dialogue can sometimes be a little clumsy. But while I was chatting to many of the side-characters it felt like a lot of the conversations should be leading into actual gameplay, perhaps fun little side-missions. They don’t, though. Venturing back into the fort for conversations can become a chore rather than a pleasure because there’s nothing of consequence, except for the fact that talking to the locals will help you level up your reputation with the handful of factions in the game.</p>



<p>There’s even the option to choose what you say, a staple of BioWare games over the years that I was happy to see return. Sadly this is a vastly stripped down version of the mechanic and your choices mean almost nothing. You can’t shape your Freelancer’s jovial tones into anything different, nor will conversations particularly alter based on your choices.</p>



<p>As for Fort Tarsis itself, it’s a lifeless area compared to the original Anthem trailers. It simply isn’t an interesting place to hang around in. There are glimmers of BioWare’s strong narrative heritage within the Fort, but it never comes to fruition. Worse, Fort Tarsis and the rest of the game feel like two entirely separate things at times.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-launch-01.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43620"/></figure>



<p>But enough of all that, lets start chatting about how it plays. Without a doubt the single best part of Anthem is leaping into the air and then, with a click of the left stick, firing the jet boosters on the back of your Javelin into life, sending you blasting into the sky. It’s the Iron Man fantasy finally done justice. The ease at which you can hurtle through the sky, dive underwater and weave around obstacles is superb. Quite honestly, despite everything else I’m going to say about Anthem, I will always cherish skimming across a lake or leaping off of cliffs before my jets roar into life.</p>



<p>But this is where we encounter Anthem’s consistent problem; getting in its own way. You see, your jets overheat quite quickly. You can alleviate this by skimming over water, or flying into lakes or through waterfalls. However, a lot of the time missions will send you down routes with no millions of gallons of water just lying around, so instead you have to drop to the ground for a few seconds and then take off again. This serves no gameplay purpose that I can think of, and thus the enjoyment of hurtling through the sky gets constantly interrupted for nothing.</p>



<p>The other thing that tends to get in the way are the loading screens. You’ve probably already heard about them since they’ve become the victim of many, many jokes on the Internet. There’re bloody legions of loading screens, and each one is slow. Entered a cave? Loading screen! Fallen behind the rest of the players? Loading screen! Want to modify your loadout? Loading screen! Picked your nose? LOADING SCREEN!</p>



<p>Things are made worse by the clumsy U.I. which seems to adore making you trawl through numerous screens to get basic information. There’s even a slight sluggishness to the menus, like they’re having to wade through treacle in order to get to your screen.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthemtitan2.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43616"/><figcaption>Titans are used over and over, but are a chore to fight</figcaption></figure>



<p>But the actual combat is rock solid. Aside from a standard selection of weapons ranging from assault rifles to shotguns – all of which feel nice and chunky to fire – each Javelin comes packing two special abilities that can be swapped out. The Ranger, for example, can fire a homing rocket and hurl grenades, while the Storm can call down a lighting storm or unleash a torrent of icy death. You also get access to an ultimate ability, as well as a support skill that helps buff yourself and your squad.</p>



<p>There’s enough agility to be found in the Javelins to give combat a nice pace. You can leap over obstacles, fly over the battlefield, hover or dodge out of the way, so getting bogged down in bad guys is almost always a case of silly decision making on the player’s behalf.</p>



<p>What’s lacking in the combat is a sense of depth, I reckon. Each Javelin is different in some ways but also too similar in others which is disappointing when there’s just four of them. And the two abilities you take into a fight just doesn’t feel like enough, nor is there much variety in said abilities. Each Javelin gets a small handful to pick from, but they’re all variations of, “point at bad guy, fire.” In short, firefights are a case of spamming your two abilities and firing your gun when they’re on cooldown.</p>



<p>There’s also an issue with the fact that your abilities are treated as loot, so you constantly have to awkwardly choose between the “best” ability in terms of raw stats or keeping your favored playstyle which might be weaker overall.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-launch-02.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43621"/></figure>



<p>I don’t feel like support gets the treatment it deserves, either. There’s no true healing skills, and most of the support skills tend to be deployed in tiny bubbles so for players to gain a benefit they have to stay inside it. This doesn’t really match the combat style Anthem seems to be going for.</p>



<p>Anthem expects you to be playing with three other people, and will in fact constantly remind you of this if you dare choose to go solo for a bit. Despite this focus on having other players in a fight the only true co-op mechanic are combos. Basically, various abilities can set enemies up for a “trigger” effect that will deal extra damage. You might freeze a soldier, for example, and then either yourself or another player might hit them with a fireball, triggering a combo and dishing out some bonus pain. I like the system and it works well, but because you can’t alter your loadout mid-mission or even prior to embarking its impossible to work together properly with random players.</p>



<p>As a looter-shooter the enemies found in Anthem tend to be bullet sponges capable of soaking up insane amounts of firepower, especially the big Titans who are a chore to battle after the first few times. It seems BioWare have used the bullet sponge design style as an excuse to skimp on enemy A.I. and behaviour sadly, since none of them exhibit any fun quirks to learn or intelligent combat tactics. Foes either charge straight at you, or just stand in the open while they unload their weapons in your general direction.</p>



<p>Mission and combat encounter design is also pretty damn poor. Almost every missions sees you flying to a point and either hunting down objects using a little radar or defending a small point while it charges up. Meanwhile, hordes of baddies will lazily spawn from thin air via nebulous ports or hives. Nearly ever missions plays out like this with no interesting set pieces or fun new mechanics getting introduced. Within just the first couple of missions Anthem has you defending a little area from waves of enemies, and from then on it never changes. The pre-release trailers showed off things like giant Strider transports collapsing, but nothing like that ever happens in the game itself.</p>



<p>Perhaps what annoys me most is that according to Anthem’s own story the relics that you often come across are capable of amazing things, including reversing gravity and turning people inside out. It’s the perfect narrative device to allow cool gameplay mechanics to get tossed into the mix. Imagine walking on the walls, or being transported to cool dimensions or maybe having to avoid chunks of the earth as its reshaped and changed. BioWare, though, reckoned that all the relics should actually do is spawn more of the same fucking things you’ve been fighting the whole time. Oh joy, doesn’t that sound so exciting?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-vga-05.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43612"/></figure>



<p>Outside of missions you can jump into Freeplay where you can fly around the world looking for crafting materials and random world events that offer up loot chests. Freeplay mode has to be played with other people, and it is kind of cool to cruise around. Again, though, Anthem gets in its own way. Take the random world events; when one pops up next to you it won’t appear on the map for any of the other players, nor can you let them know about it without using voice chat. Too often I wound up in a big fight for some good loot while the other three players flew around oblivious to the opportunity.</p>



<p>It’s also impossible to start Contracts or Stronghold missions from Freeplay which is a massive missed opportunity. Instead, you have to jump back to Fort Tarsis or the oddly pointless launch bay, which means a lengthy loading screen, before launching a new expedition which results in yet another long loading screen. It’s slow and frustrating.</p>



<p>Indeed, Anthem makes a lot of basic tasks much slower and harder than they should be, although Bioware at least seem to know this and are patching in new features such as being able to jump straight to the expedition screen from anywhere within Fort Tarsis. The map is a prime example; it’s bloody useless and you can’t set custom waypoints. Finding your way around in Freeplay is a pain in the arse because of this. You also can’t change your loadout during a mission, instead you have to go back to Fort Tarsis and fumble through the weirdly laggy menus.</p>



<p>Then there’s stupid little things like how when you’re buying crafting materials you can’t tell how much you already have.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-launch-03.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43610"/></figure>



<p>I’m also genuinely baffled by the fact that you can’t check out loot during a mission. Instead you have no idea what you’ve picked up until you get to the mission end screen, which removes the beautiful joy of stumbling across an awesome new gun mid-mission and happily telling your friends about it. Oddly, the pre-release trailers showed players examining AND equipping new loot out in the field. Why the hell was this changed?</p>



<p>Right, speaking of the loot let’s tackle that, because while Anthem is a loot-driven game I’m not entirely sure if BioWare knew that. The simple way of saying this is that picking up new gear is boring. New guns look exactly like their previous versions with just two or three variations of each model, and the stat increases tend to be small and hard to notice. Things don’t improve as you level up and start getting rarer loot. Even Masterwork items aren’t exciting as they feel and look like every other bit of loot, just with better bonuses. I never once got a new piece of gear that made me grin ear-to-ear, and in a looter-shooter that’s really the most important thing. If Borderlands 2 can still make me whoop with delight at a new gun, then why the hell can’t Anthem?</p>



<p>With that all said, it is still fun to carefully min-max your gear, even if the lack of a proper stat page makes me furious, as does the lack of information in general. How much fire resistance do I have? Pfft, no idea. What’s my total combo damage buff? Dunno. Still, there’s just enough room to create different builds and experiment a little. Hopefully new abilities and Javelins will be added with more varied gear for some truly exciting builds.</p>



<p>Customization of the Javelins themselves is woefully underdeveloped. No new armor or vinyls will drop out on the field, rather you can purchase them using in-game currency or real-world cash from the “featured” stores. Armour, though, is severely limited with just a few basic pieces per Javelin, and the fact that it can’t be gotten through loot drops feels like a dumb decision. As a result everyone looks mostly the same at the moment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthem-screenshot-launch-04.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43611"/></figure>



<p>Quickplay does exactly what it says on the tin, dropping you into a random mission or Stronghold. The problem here is that the game doesn’t take into account your own position in the story, so it’s possible for a lowly level 2 player to find themselves in the last story mission by accident. I also constantly encountered Quickplay missions where the objectives weren’t updating and thus the missions couldn’t be completed.</p>



<p>On the topic of technical problem, there are a number of them. Aside from constant connection drop-outs booting me back to the main menu, I also had a few crashes, long delays between objectives updating, doors locking other players out, events not triggering correctly and a bunch more that were minor but frustrating. There’s also a sort of lag that exists between enemies being shot and the health bar updating. Oh, and sometimes the health bar just wouldn’t show up at all. I’ve also ran into instances of the final piece of a Relic I needed to collect not spawning and the radar for finding it disappearing. Numerous other issues have been reported by other players, too.<br></p>



<p>Finally, let’s chat about the end-game, or more precisely the lack of one. Once you reach level 30 you’ll unlock Grandmaster difficulties and a higher chance of getting rare items, so that’s all good. However, all you get to play are three Stronghold missions which are basically about 30-60 minutes each and culminate in boss battles. Aside from the constantly generated generic contract missions and Freeplay you’re expected to replay those three Stronghold missions over and over again. And to add insult to injury one of those Stronghold’s is just the final story mission all over again. None of the Stronghold’s introduce anything new or exciting, either. It’s the same things you’ve been doing the whole game.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/anthemcolossus.jpg.adapt_.crop16x9.818p.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-43617"/></figure>



<p>For a game with such a colossal budget and lengthy development time the sheer lack of end-game content in a game of this type is baffling. So far BioWare have stated that new content isn’t coming for a few months, leaving current players to grind away.</p>



<p>Somehow within the near seven years it took for Anthem to launch both EA and BioWare have seemingly ignored the lessons taught by Destiny, The Division and even Warframe. I have no doubt in my mind that Anthem probably began life as something very different and became a “games as a service” product somewhere along the way. It feels stitched together in too many places.<br></p>



<p>Here’s the kicker, though; despite its myriad problems I actually kind of like Anthem. I found myself sinking into its simple gameplay loops. But there are too many basic design problems holding Anthem back. As a live service game it’s hard to know what the future holds for BioWare’s looter-shooter, but right now I’d recommend you wait a while before picking Anthem up. In its current state it has okay combat, poor enemy design, boring missions, dull loot and enough loading screens to let you catch up on your reading.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Red Dead Redemption 2 Review – Rootin’, Tootin’ And Some Shootin’</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/25/red-dead-redemption-2-review-rootin-tootin-and-some-shootin/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 13:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=104</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>Talk about pressure. It was eight years ago that Red Dead Redemption, a sequel to the oft forgotten Red Dead Revolver, hit consoles and took the world by storm. Rockstar are known for their craft, but even by their standards RDR felt special, a western in video game form that told the story of John Marston, the gruffest man who ever did gruff. Eight years is a long time to wait for a sequel. Well, a prequel, actually, as now we delve into the infamous gang of Dutch Van der Linde, the very same bunch that John was ultimately tasked with taking down eventually. With the narrative shadow of Marston looming over everything, can the game still tell a compelling story while improving on the wild west themes? Yes, yes, and a thousand times yes.</p>



<p>Reviewing Red Dead Redemption 2 feels nigh on impossible without at least addressing the controversy surrounding developer Rockstar’s alleged working hours that may have been pushing staff to perform 100-hour work weeks. The concept of “crunch” time in the game industry, where developers ramp up their working hours near the launch of a game, is sadly not an uncommon or new concept, so to focus a review around it while having not covered in other reviews of triple-A titles that most likely were made under the same conditions would be a silly choice, I feel. So, while I may mention the controversy here or there I’m ultimately going to be reviewing the game on its own merits.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-26.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(6)" class="wp-image-35321"/></figure>



<p>Red Dead Redemption 2 might be the most pure form of roleplaying game, not because you can invest points in skills or spend hours creating your character but because Rockstar’s obsessive attention to detail in almost every aspect of the graphics, animations, audio and little things serve to put you into the boots of protagonist Arthur Morgan and into his world in a way I don’t think has been matched before. It’s a cliche at this point to say that a game world is “alive” but the sentence feels entirely perfect to describe this digital version of the wild west. The sheer amount of animations, for example, is simply staggering as Rockstar have seemingly given Arthur an animation for everything he does, from the brutal skinning of a hunted animal to the lethargic walk when he hasn’t slept to the way he grabs a gun from his horse’s saddle. It creates the feeling that Arthur is genuinely a part of the world rather than just being an avatar for the player and because of that, it’s easy to become utterly absorbed. You won’t mind the limited fast travel because that time it takes to ride from place to place on your cherished horse feels earned.</p>



<p>And damn, does it look absolutely amazing. There’s some sort of sorcery going on here because this is easily the best looking open-world title to date and one of the best looking games of all time. Gorgeous lighting and weather effects constantly took my breath away, especially when you get a mixture of fog in a forest with some rays of light piercing the treetops. an incredible level of detail and practically non-existent pop-in despite the huge size of the map and the vast vistas. Simply put, this is a technical masterpiece and I’m hoping that Rockstar bring it to PC so that we can see what the raw power of that platform can do.</p>



<p>Of course, it’s not perfect. Take the HDR implementation, for example, which is utter crap. With HDR enabled the image takes on a washed-out look and doesn’t appear to have the extra colour graduation and detail that good HDR use should provide. Disabling it results in a much more vibrant image. For a more detailed breakdown of this strange HDR usage check out the Eurogamer article where they determined that Rockstar simply tricked the PS4 and Xbox One into believing an HDR image was being outputted when really there wasn’t.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-25.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(5)" class="wp-image-35320"/></figure>



<p>Furthering Rockstar’s laser-like focus on crafting the most detailed world possible a while raft of features has been introduced that add considerable busywork to your life. You can clean your guns, for example, to keep their stats as high as possible. Meanwhile, Arthur himself needs to eat and sleep in order to maintain his peak physical condition, and while you can completely ignore both of these things you’ll take health and stamina penalties for doing so, with both refilling slower than they could. Your horse also needs to be fed and brushed otherwise its stats will take a hit, too, and you also need to bond with it by patting it, calming it when predators are nearby and doing other things.</p>



<p>There was frequently little moments that delighted me. At one point I accidentally knocked a can of food off a barrel just as I pressed the button to grab it, and Arthur smoothly grabbed it out of the air as it fell. It’s a tiny piece of design and animation that may never even be used in someone’s playthrough, and even if it is they may not notice it, yet it’s a testimont to how much effort and love was put into this game. And the more I played the more I noticed, like how in a small encounter a prisoner asked me to shoot his shackles but instead, completely off the cuff, I decided to capture him and take him to the nearby sheriff’s office where I was rewarded. The game never mentioned this was something I could do, yet somewhere in Rockstar someone considered this eventuality. Later I painfully discovered that coming up behind a spooked horse equals a kick in the head. Then even later I found out that lawmen will come and carry away corpses after a firefight. And even later than that, and totally unrelated to said corpses, I discovered that members of your gang will sometimes appear to get you out of jail, complete with hilarious cutscenes.</p>



<p>There’s a price to Rockstar’s slavish attention to detail, though, and I’m not just referring to the controversey surrounding employees working insane hours. No, in this instance I’m referring to the game’s pace which at times can feel glacial, both in terms of how willing it is to take its time and how the level of detail can make simple tasks a lengthy process. The first few times you go hunting is an engrossing affair since crouching is slow going and animals easily spooked, but later on the whole thing can feel tedius and slow due to the long animations for skinning, carrying and stowing the body on your horse. Likewise remembering to clean your gun, eat food, brush your horse and everything else can become a never ending series of chores, and if you find yourself stuck without your horse being unable to summon it instantly that can be a real drag.</p>



<p>These things are not a problem as such, but they do mean that Red Dead Redemption 2 has a very methodical pace that needs you to be in the right mood to enjoy it. There were a couple of times I fired up the game and quickly realised that I just couldn’t be bothered to ride the long distances often required or clean my gun or got annoyed by the fact that my horse couldn’t be summoned unless it was relatively close. The busywork serves to immerse you into the world, but there are times when you want to jump in and just have some fun. But it’s unfair to criticize the game for this. Ultimately, films are the same; you don’t always want a fast-paced action film, but sometimes you don’t want a slow-burn, either.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-21.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(1)" class="wp-image-35316"/></figure>



<p>That slow feeling is present throughout the story, too, which is happy to take its time. There is an overarching plot, but really the focus is purely on Arthur Morgan and the rest of the Van De Linde gang as they try to make their way in a world that’s changing. The theme of the wild west giving way to cities and government and our lead character having no place in it is immediately reminiscent of the last Red Dead game which did give me pause for concern initially as I wondered if Rocktsar was going to rehash the same stuff, but have no fear because despite a few stumbles here and there this is a fantastic tale that takes the theme in different directions and crafts a great lead character in Arthur Morgan. At first he almost appears to be another John Marston: gruff, rough looking yet handsome in his way and quite quiet compared to many of the others around him, but it doesn’t take long for Arthur to carve out his own place and I almost instantly became wholly engrossed in his story and his relationship with surrogate father/gang leader Dutch Van Der Lin.</p>



<p>The gang is made up of about a dozen members, and so naturally not all of them get a heap of time in the main storyline, but thankfully each person feels distinct and conversations that they have with others and with yourself at camp really help flesh them out. Rockstar often goes for over-the-top characters in their GTA series, so it was refreshing to see them stick to more believable people here with just a few outlandish personalities scattered around here and there. The sense of camaraderie and family is palpable, too, through the bickering, insults, compliments and parties that occur when you pull off a big job. Almost every mission involves at least one of the other gang members, giving you time to bond with them during long rides to the objective.</p>



<p>The narrative manages to deliver a lot of funny moments as well as genuinely emotional moments, too. We pick up with the gang just after a large job has gone to hell, so now they’re on the run from the Pinkerton Agency and the local law. Your first few hours are spent slogging through a savage snow storm before finally getting into the open world proper, and from then on most of the story is spent depicting a series of major screw ups that leave the gang reeling. It’s fascinating, exciting stuff that delivers solid story arcs for both Arthur himself and Dutch.</p>



<p>It also juggles the inclusion of John Marston (lead character in the previous Red Dead Redemption) very well. Since this is a prequel to Red Dead Redemption John is still very much part of the gang, but Rockstar manages to balance his screen time nicely so that we get to learn even more about him while never feeling like too much focus is being given to him. He’s treated as another member of the gang, for the most part, but the knowledge of what is coming enriches the experience in a lot of ways. It makes me want to play Red Dead Redemption again.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-22.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(2)" class="wp-image-35317"/></figure>



<p>Outstanding voice acting is present throughout the game with nary a poor or out of place performance to be found, and layered on top of that is the sparse use of excellent music.</p>



<p>But now we need to start getting into the core gameplay. Despite the massive amount of development time that went into RDR2 it genuinely baffles me that the game controls so poorly and has frankly clumsy combat. This isn’t a new thing: John Marston in Red Dead Redemption felt like a barrel that you were attempting to roll around, and things didn’t really improve with GTA V, either. It’s strange to me that eight years after the last Red Dead game the controls and movement don’t seem to have changed. Sure, on the one hand, the hefty feel of the controls does make Arthur feel more connected to the world, but on the other hand it also constantly feels like you’re attempting to manoeuvre a tank around one of those tiny little second-hand shops. You’ll constantly overshoot things because Rockstar wanted to animate those extra few steps needed to break into a run or stop, and trying to pick up a specific item can frequently lead to you having to walk Arthur around in a small circle to find the prompt. For me, this is one of those times when realism should not have been the focus.</p>



<p>These cumbersome controls find their way into the combat which honestly doesn’t feel like its improved all that much in the eight years since the prior Red Dead game. A tap of the shoulder button will get Arthur into cover, but ducking behind something or moving from protection to protection feels clunky, while the generous default auto-aim will literally lock onto a target as soon as you pull the left trigger. Thankfully you can switch the auto-aim off or just tone it down, but regardless the combat never feels all that good. However, it’s far from being bad and if you spend some time in the options you can improve the aiming, and the general clumsiness gets glossed over by the superb sound design that lends guns a satisfying sense of power, the look and noise of wood splintering as bullets nearly obliterate your brain and the yells of everybody involved.</p>



<p>The control scheme itself is pretty insane as well. Rockstar’s games have often had unusual control schemes that shun industry standards, but here it feels like it’s taken to the next level due to the sheer amount of different contextual actions and things that you need to do. It’s hardly intuitive, though you can delve into the options and tweak a few things to help. Eventually, you do get used to it, but even after dozens of hours I still found myself having to look at the tooltips popping up.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-27.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(7)" class="wp-image-35322"/></figure>



<p>Of course, there’s an absolutely shit-load of stuff to do outside of the main storyline missions, including robbing stage coaches and homesteads, bounty hunting, train robberies and just mugging whoever happens to be passing by. Then there’s the wealth of little interactions back at camp and the random events that can occur within the world which can lead to saving some poor folk, just giving a beggar some money, being ambushed for the bounty you’re carrying, people attempting to rob you and a bunch of other that continues to amaze and astound me. Finally, there are the Stranger mission which feature most of the outlandishly entertaining and barmy characters which lead into a series of missions. I always looked forward to coming back to a character’s storyline and seeing where it would go next. Hell, one even involved helping a professor as he tried to create the electric chair with hilarious results.</p>



<p>However, I also appreciate that the map isn’t littered with hundreds of little icons vying for your attention. Too many open world games clutter the map with cut and paste activities, so to see a relatively clean mini-map is refreshing.</p>



<p>To the game’s credit, most missions follow the same basic template of travelling to a place while listening to a lengthy chunk of conversation/exposition and then usually winding up in a gunfight it manages to dress up the core mechanics in a variety of interesting ways. One mission has Arthur heading out with his two mentors, Dutch and Hosea, to go fishing before they get caught up in a shootout, but instead of ending things their you get the choice to carry on with the fishing trip, leading to a peaceful sequence where Arthur just gets to spend time in the company of two men who practically raised him. There are also stealth sections, chases, high-class parties and so much more mixed in, and while the heavily scripted nature of the missions can sometimes feel too limiting this is still a superb example of how to create missions that use the same mechanics yet do so smartly to keep the player interested.</p>



<p>Your gang’s camp is a respite between missions and a charming place just to hang out and chat with everyone else, but there are also some gameplay systems woven into it. Specifically, the camp needs to be kept stocked with food, ammo and medicine as well as money donated from the gang members which can, in turn, be used to buy improvements or restock items. You can also turn in hunted animals to help keep everyone fed. Finally, there are various chores like chopping wood and topping up the wash basins that you can do to help keep morale high, which will result in gang members donating more cash and supplies. The whole camp system is a cool idea on paper, but it’s one of the very few aspects of Red Dead 2 that feels undercooked compared to everything else. Donating cash was rarely a problem because cash is actually pretty easy to come by anyway and the game even hands you a lot of guns for free, and the morale system feels nebulous at best. Sure, a higher morale means everyone appears happier, but the extra donations amount to little since the rest of the gang won’t come close to putting in what you do anyway. With this said I never did let the camp go without full supplies and healthy funds, so perhaps if you allow things to get too bad there are serious consequences.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot_2018-11-06-screens-red-dead-redemption-24.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C411&amp;ssl=1" alt="Screenshot_2018-11-06 Screens - Red Dead Redemption 2(4)" class="wp-image-35319"/></figure>



<p>There’s a bit of a weird disconnect between the gang attempting to score big so that they can leave their lives behind and the amount of cash you have in your pockets. At first, things feel exactly like you would imagine; guns, supplies and a good horse are all expensive things, so robbing stagecoaches or just random people on the road for a few dollars feels exactly like the outlaw life you’re meant to be leading. But it doesn’t take long before the game hands you piles of cash, making later moments where Dutch comments on a potentially big job earning them thousands a little funny when you have a couple of thousand dollars sitting in your satchel. Damn, Dutch, if you wanted some beer money you just needed to ask.</p>



<p>The same sense of disconnect exists in the health and stamina systems. Having to remember to eat, smoke and drink to maintain your stats is an intriguing idea even if, as we’ve discussed, it adds a lot of busywork, but it also feels like Rockstar didn’t want to commit fully to the idea so you can pretty much ignore it without noticing too hard a hit on your performance. Perhaps some sort of difficulty selection would have allowed players to tailor their experience so that they could ramp up the effects of eating for a more immersive journey.</p>



<p>Given the scope of the game, it’s not surprising that there are some glitches and issues to be found, though it’s actually impressively polished as a whole. I encountered quite a number of bugged animations where the game couldn’t quite decide how to handle things, moments where the controls just seemed to go insane and stop working, people getting stuck and other things. I never once hit anything game breaking or truly serious, though.</p>



<p>Reviewing something like this almost feels like a pointless waste of time since it’s going to sell like hotcakes anyway, right? Still, I couldn’t resist talking about this beautiful piece of video game art, and that’s what it is. This is a masterpiece in immersion and world creation, using an incredible level of detail and thought to draw you into the character of Arthur Morgan and make you feel like you’re a part of the wild west. It’s not perfect and to hail it as such would be silly. The controls and combat stand as the two weakest elements of the game, and while it’s understandable that Rockstar wants to go with that weighty feel it’s one of the areas where I wish they had gone with playability over realism. There are a bunch of small niggles here and there, too, plus a few duff notes in the story, but these all pale in comparison to what Rockstar has accomplished here. Red Dead Redemption 2 is special, a spectacular wild west tale that grabs you and then doesn’t let go until dozens of hours later after its sucker-punched you with a few emotional blows, so many tales unique to you and a hell of an ending. This is open-world gaming at its finest, and to that, I tip my hat.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dead Cells Review – A Good Day To Die Again And Again</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/25/dead-cells-review-a-good-day-to-die-again-and-again/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 13:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=101</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<h3>Dead Cells is a rogue-like or rogue-lite or rogue-something depending on the exact definition that you opt to go by, meaning that whenever you die you’ll just respawn at the very start but having hopefully managed to make some progress along the way by grabbing lots of Cells from dead enemies, shiny new blueprints and maybe even a Rune or two. In other words, this genre is a bit like banging your head off of a brick wall with the goal being to break through. Keep doing it long enough and you might just manage to break the wall. But at what cost? Concussion, I would imagine, at the very least.</h3>



<p>In a lot of ways this is an apt metaphor for a game that proved itself to be a prime example of how to do Early Access; try something, get better, push further, go back, get better, push further. Dead Cells spent a good amount of time under the Early Access banner and the sheer level of polish makes it abundantly clear that the developers used the time well. Other companies take note, this is how you do it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/20180812170713_1.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C373&amp;ssl=1" alt="20180812170713_1" class="wp-image-34953"/></figure>



<p>Explaining how you never truly die is the fact that you’re some sort of sentient green gloop that hijacks a fresh, headless corpse, the supply of which is seemingly endless. Whenever this body gets destroyed by the denizens of the various levels you’ll be fighting through you’ll just plop down to the ground through a special tube in the ceiling, grab a fresh new corpse and then proceed to delve back into the battle like nothing ever happened.</p>



<p>The story really isn’t the focus of the game, but for those willing to explore the levels there are special rooms that offer glimpses into what happened, and it’s surprisingly interesting stuff at times. That’s largely because the details are left to the imagination, though.</p>



<p>On a slightly related story note, for a mute character with limited gestures the developers have somehow made your avatar quite funny. There were a couple of moments where it made me laugh by giving the thumbs up when a character asked something.</p>



<p>So, what you’ll be doing is spending your time navigating a series of 2D levels via some light platforming and plenty of violence. Combat is easy to grasp but that doesn’t mean it isn’t without its own little nuances that you need to learn. You get two main weapons that include melee and ranged weapons such as swords, spears, bows, ice shards and more, and a single button for each is all you need. You can also pick up a shield if that’s your preference. You can also find two special abilities that get mapped to the triggers when playing on the controller, which is recommended, and these can be stuff like a deployable turret, traps for stopping an enemy in their tracks or even being able to syphon health for a while. Finally, you have a dodge button for getting out of trouble, and a ground stomp for when you want to introduce yourself from a high perch.</p>



<p>The reason it works is because great pains have been made to ensure each weapon and each enemy feels different. It won’t take you long to develop your own preferences when it comes to weapons and weapon combinations, and extra modifiers only add more intrigue to the situation. You might get lucky and wind up with your favourite weapons as well as having one modifier that freezes enemies and another that deals out 175% more damage to frozen foes, but quite often you’ll also have to make do with weapons you don’t like and modifiers that don’t click together very well. No matter what you end up with, though, it changes the way you play, which I really love.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/20180814201601_1.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C373&amp;ssl=1" alt="20180814201601_1" class="wp-image-34957"/></figure>



<p>All the horrible bad guys you’ll be fighting change the way you handle things, too. They all have their own behaviours that you’ll learn, and sometimes seem clearly suited to be tackled with a specific type of weapon. That just means you have to improvise with whatever you have to hand. Hell, I’ve sunk over 20+ hours into the game and there are still enemies who I try to avoid like the plague because I’ve just not figured them out.</p>



<p>In short, combat just feels really, really bloody good.</p>



<p>Special items and rooms help out along the way. Magical scrolls, for example, let you boost the damage of one of the three colour-coded weapon types by 15% every time you snap one up, and perhaps more importantly also bolsters your HP by up to 60%. More health in a game like this is always good, after all. But interestingly, while these scrolls will always increase the damage of one color of weapon by 15%, the HP values vary based on how many times you’ve selected that color. In other words, if you focus exclusively on ramping up the stabbiness of your stabby stick you’ll get considerably less health in return. Hmm, decisions, decisions.</p>



<p>Then there are the frustrating timed doors that will automatically lock if you don’t make it to them in a certain amount of time, forcing you to speed run a level like a lunatic if you want to snag the sweet goodies inside. Again, there’s an interesting decision to be made here; do you hoover up everything in a level in order to gain as many scrolls and Cells as possible, or you do run for the timed doors?</p>



<p>Cells basically act as the currency you’ll be using between levels in order to do a number of things, such as upgrading your weapons and reforging them to get new effects. But mostly you’ll be giving them over to the Collector, a being that will happily accept your payment in order to unlock a variety of stuff. Firstly, there is a small array of permanent upgrades, including the incredibly important ability to use your health potion multiple times, an option that becomes very expensive very quickly but is oh so worth it. Or you might invest some of your Cells into being given a randomly selected weapon every time you respawn. Again, this is fairly vital or else you have to make do with basic training weapons until you can find some more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/20180813202742_1.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C373&amp;ssl=1" alt="20180813202742_1" class="wp-image-34954"/></figure>



<p>The sweetest, juiciest loot you can arguably find, outside of the most powerful versions of weapons, are the blueprints that can open up new gear and upgrades for you to purchase at The Collector. There’s a dastardly catch, though; like Cells and everything else you pick up along the way, blueprints disappear if you die, so in order to keep it you need to finish the level. Again, choices; run like hell for the exit with what you have? Or keep exploring?</p>



<p>The game almost mocks you with all the stuff you can get your grubby mitts on by having a little section where you respawn covered in hanging bottles that will fill up with the various upgrades and weapons you manage to acquire. Over time you’ll get more options. It’s slow going sometimes, especially since some of the best, and arguably most vital upgrades, are incredibly expensive. This, though, forms the core of the game. You have to grind. You have to be willing to die again and again in order to make it a little bit farther, and for a lot of people that is not going to be fun. That’s fine. You need to be somebody who can fail, take a deep breath, maybe utter a rude word and carry on.</p>



<p>At some point, I became aware that the game was quietly tricking me. You see, the movement feels so wonderfully precise and responsive. You move quickly, stop exactly where you want to, dodge on command – it just feels so damn right, from the very first moment you pick up the controller. That’s the trick; it lulls you into a sense of confidence. On a good run the controls let you enter that mysterious and indescribable sense of Zen where you can seemingly do no wrong, commit no crime. You get cocky. And then the game smacks you around a bit. Maybe you just got cocky facing off against enemies or a boss you’ve fought time after time, or maybe you stupidly ran headfirst into a new threat because you feel like you’re videogame Jesus. It doesn’t matter, the game has tricked you. It tricked me. I like that. I like that a lot.</p>



<p>It’s a game capable of providing immense satisfaction and equally devastating defeat, where a single mistake can lead to you losing a bunch of Cells and a rare blueprint dropped by an enemy. When these things happen it’s almost physically painful. Dead Cells manages to coax a lot of emotions and reactions from me; tension, dread, excitement, sweat, relief and raw anger.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/20180813205740_1.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C373&amp;ssl=1" alt="20180813205740_1" class="wp-image-34955"/></figure>



<p>But no game is without flaws and Dead Cells does not break that trend. Unsurprisingly, the biggest issue it faces is repetition, after all by the genre’s very nature it demands that you replay the same things over and over again in the pursuit of that perfect run. Levels get randomized as do the specific locations and mixes of enemy types, but that only only do so much to alleviate the feeling of running through the same place fighting the same bad guys.</p>



<p>The other problem is that pure luck sometimes plays a role in how things go. Not getting decent weapon combinations can leave you hurting, as can a lack of scrolls or just the levels making a speedrun for the doors awkward.</p>



<p>Perhaps the biggest thing you need to know about Dead Cells and why it’s so damn good is that it practically embodies the concept of, “just one more go. One more run. Just. One.” I can’t really explain it, especially since there are times when it will barely feel like you’ve made a dent in the game despite doing a dozen runs. But everything just feels so good that you want to keep playing. It’s never unfair, harshly punishes your mistakes but then dangles another carrot in front of you, and like a masochistic idiot you’ll try to grab it.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forza Horizon 4 Review – Better Than Ever</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/25/forza-horizon-4-review-better-than-ever/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 13:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=98</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<p>Tossing a Ford Cosworth with a sickening amount of power around dirt bends in the U.K. sounds like something I’d like to do on the weekend, but given that I can barely afford to survive on Pot Noodles it’s also a bit of a pipe-dream. Well, nearly, because for the fourth iteration on the massively successful Horizon spin-off series developer Playground have opted to head to the United Kingdom, so when the opportunity to pick a supped up Cosworth presents itself I don’t hesitate. You can keep your Bugatti Veyron.</p>



<p>The basic premise remains the same as this time the Horizon festival of motorsport arrives in the U.K, once again meaning we get a big open world and a wealth of awesome cars to drive around in. The map takes the city of Edinburh and a chunk of the surrounding area, squishes it together and then lets you loose. As a Scottish lad born and raised I know the city of Edinburgh well, and driving around the digital recreation of its streets is a genuine thrill, even if certain things are missing and the whole place has been condensed massively. We also get swathes of rolling country side full of twisty turns and smaller towns to blast through, although I admit to being a little dissapointed that the Playground never decided to come further north into Scotland to experience some of the awesome roads that can be found here. Maybe they were afraid we’d paint ourselves blue and use their skulls as decorations. To be fair, that is not entirely outside the realms of possibility.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forza-horizon-4_senna-autumn.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Senna Autumn" class="wp-image-35237"/></figure>



<p>Admiteddly since I actually live in the U.K. it’s a bit less enjoyable to cruise around the roads and the many roadworks. Australia was a much more intriguing prospect in Horizon 3 since I was largely unfamiliar with the landscape, but I suppose this just means that people outside of the U.K. will now get to experience our country roads.</p>



<p>One of the big selling points of this year’s Horizon is that the weather will change every week of real time, each new season altering the way cars handle and the environment itself. In winter, for example, certain lakes will freeze over entirely so that you can drive on them and the roads will be coated in lovely, white, powdery death that will send you scarpering to the upgrade shop for some snow tyres post-haste. Now, these seasonal changes don’t radically alter the game like the advertising would love to have you believe, but it’s still a really fun feature and the introductory first few hours speeds up the transitions so that you can get a taste of every season. Driving the same event in summer before then trying it in winter feels different and looks different enough that you could almost be fooled into thinking you were competing in a completely new race. It’s a shame that you can’t swap between the seasons at will, though you can pick a season when creating a custom event.</p>



<p>There’s a reason for not being able to swap as you want, however, and that’s due to Playground’s continued desire to introduce more online elements into their series. Now when you fire up the game you’re automatically popped into an online server with a bunch of other folks. Whenever the season changes new events will be added to the map, so while I was playing, for example, winter arrived and I wound up in a championship based around driving super saloons in the slippery conditions. Most of these new races are remixes of existing events, but the tightened restraints on what you can drive and the bonus rewards offered for participating in championships make them feel worth your time and are a nice encouragement to keep coming back to the game, as are the daily and weekly challenges.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forzahorizon4_gamescom_wm_02.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Jump" class="wp-image-35233"/></figure>



<p>The way you progress through the game has been reworked slightly since Horizon 3 and certainly for the better. In Horizon 3 completing events would open up even more races to partake in but it was a system that could often mean doing things that you didn’t enjoy. In this new system, though, competing in road races, for example, will open more events in the same category and there’s always plenty of XP available in your chosen discipline to advance the main career. You might still have to mix in some other things here or there, but for the most part you can now more freely focus on the style of racing that you enjoy most, working all the way to the top before ever checking out something else.</p>



<p>The show-stopping Showcase events are back and as awesome as ever despite their scripted nature, pitting you against stuff like a massive hovercraft or even the famous Flying Scotsman train (as seen in Harry Potter) as it chugs its way into Edinburgh. They’re a great way to break up the action and a bring a scripted, cinematic flair to the racing genre as a whole. I mean, where else would you get to race an Aston Martin Vulcan against the Vulcan bomber, or even barrel over the countryside in Warthog lifted straight from the Halo games? I just wish there were even more Showcase events to play through.</p>



<p>For some added fun there are also several special Horizon stories, each of them offering 10&nbsp; chapters to blast through. You can be a stunt driver working on a film, help out a friend with his brand new supercar rental service or even team up with a streamer who wants to replicate their 10 favorite car moments from videogames, a brilliantly meta way for Playground to pay tribute to the various games that have influenced the creation of the Horizon series. The dialogue in all these stories isn’t going to be winning any awards, but the added context to what you’re doing is quite welcome.</p>



<p>And of course, you’ve got oodles and oodles and poodles of standard races scattered across the map. It’s almost too much as before long your map will become crammed full of icons of all vying for your attention. On top of it all is the fact you can make up your own events using the Blueprint system or use ones created by the community.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forzahorizon4_gamescom_wm_04.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Winter Trucks" class="wp-image-35235"/></figure>



<p>Oh but wait, there’s more. Forzathon events occur every hour where a blimp will turn up on the map causing everybody on the server to go racing toward it so that they can partake in three challenges for bonus rewards. Sadly these challenges are a bit dull, like having to repeatedly race through a speed camera in order to accumulate a certain amount, but it’s still cool to see a bunch of players turn up in the same spot, and you get those epic moments where you’re racing along and suddenly get joined by a jeep crashing through a nearby wall.</p>



<p>In total, you can have up to 70 players in a single online session, although I’d say 20-40 tends to be more typical. Smartly by default these other players will ghost straight through you unless you’re specifically grouped together so you never have to worry about people making your life hell unless you want them to. However, since you’re put into an online session by default when you load up the game there’s a sense that everybody is just going about their own business most of the time, generally ignoring when you pass by on the roads. You can challenge them to a spur of the moment race with a tap of X, but I generally found that most people were not interested. Likewise trying to kick off a multiplayer race could be pretty hit or miss.</p>



<p>When you do get some racing going with other folks, or fire up King of the Hill or one of the other game types, it’s a whole lot of fast fun, though. There are a few issues with the checkpoint system and other players potentially forcing you into missing them, at which point the game awkwardly dumps you back on the track, but because you’ve lost momentum it becomes bloody hard to play catch up.</p>



<p>Still not enough pure content? Well, there are also drift areas scattered around the map (now with regular traffic ghosted out so they can’t ruin your run) as well as speed cameras, awesome jumps and barn finds where you can unlock classic cars. I swear, doing everything in this game would take dozens upon dozens of hours.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forzahorizon4_gamescom_wm_03.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Edinburgh Race" class="wp-image-35234"/></figure>



<p>Wheelspins return and are given out at a rapid rate, once again offering up a chance to win bonus cash or even brand new cars, including a bunch of rare Forza edition models that you can’t buy normally. However, mixing things up are tonnes of clothes for the avatars and stupid dance moves, so now more often than not you just seem to win boring crap rather than exciting new vehicles or piles of cash that you can use to buy…well, exciting new vehicles. It’s more than a little anti-climatic to win a Superspin (three prizes instead of the normal one) only to walk away with a pair of glittery shoes, a new shirt and a cowbow hat.</p>



<p>So, I mentioned clothes and dance moves for your avatar. You now get to choose from a very limited set of facial types at the start of the game and perform some limited customization before going out into the world. From then on your main customisation comes from the clothes that you win, and you’ll get to show off your stuff at the end of events where your digitial chump or chumpette will perform whatever daft dance you’ve chosen for them. It’s an alright inclusion to the series, but frankly in Horizon it’s the cars that are the characters and so your avatars feel a bit boring and pointless.</p>



<p>Perhaps if Playground had opted to go further down the Test Drive Unlimited route and let you walk around a car showroom or your houses then it would have made more sense. Sadly the only nod toward Test Drive is that you spent cash to buy houses across the map, including Edinburgh castle if you like, but these just act as glorified fast travel points, and failing that things to spend your ever-growing pile of cash on.</p>



<p>Or you could just buy a crap-load more cars from the 430+ plus that are in the base game, ranging from some rally raid trucks to actual racing trucks to insane hypercars to the Ford Cosworth, as well as some other unique beauties. It’s an extensive collection of machinery to drool over, although there are some notable exclusions such as Toyota. The fun doesn’t stop there as there’s an extensive list of upgrades that you can apply, all the way up to swapping the engine out or the entire drivetrain if you like. It’s almost a shame that the game is so generous with its cash because you can usually afford to buy a car then slap every high-end upgrade on it instantly rather than having to slowly but steadily earn the money to build your dream machine. Then you can move on to the wealth of tuning options so that you can turn your beast into the ultimate drift car, the perfect off-roader or the king of the drag strip.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forza-horizon-4_night-drift.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Night Drift" class="wp-image-35236"/></figure>



<p>Once you’ve finished tinkering with the mechanical side of things there’s always the awesome creation suite where you can paint your new ride, apply decals and potentially spend dozens of hours just honing your art before putting it up for the community to use. Or you could just do what I do and use the hard work of others because I have all the artistic talent of a small tomato.</p>



<p>You could always potentially skip the tuning and upgrading side of things to by heading to the community marketplace where you can bid on other player’s cars that they want to sell off, or you can simply download a pre-defined tuning setup for your car. The sense of community here is awesome as there’s a seemingly infinite supply of talented people who love to create tuning setups or amazing paint jobs or entire cars that have been upgraded, painted and tuned to within an inch of their lives.</p>



<p>So far I’ve spent a lot of words not talking about the actual driving, and that’s partially because it almost feels redundant. After having crafted three prior games in the franchise and with Horizon 3 being as great as it was we all know that Playground is simply superb when it comes to crafting their handling models. Nothing has changed here in that regard. The more sim handling of the mainline Forza series is taken and then tweaked so that cars retain their sense of weight and connection with the roads while also being more accessible and forgiving so that you can powerslide around bends or leap off of massive cliffs. The resulting blend strikes what I believe to be a near perfect balance, managing to feel real and believable with plenty of room for pure skill yet also being friendly to newcomers and more bombastic.</p>



<p>Considering the vast roster of cars to buy it’s impressive that they all feel different, their individual characters shining through so that you’ll always be able to pick out favourites. There’s a world of difference between driving a twitchy hypercar that sticks to the road like glue at high speeds and a touchy RWD beast, and the off-road handling has been further developed since Horizon 3 so that it could now nearly be mistaken for a dedicated rally game.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/forza-horizon-4_snowy-trucks.jpg?zoom=1.25&amp;resize=890%2C501&amp;ssl=1" alt="Forza Horizon 4 Snowy Trucks" class="wp-image-35240"/></figure>



<p>If you’re using a controller you get a pleasing amount of feedback through vibration, giving you constant information about what your car is doing. Plug in a steering wheel and the force feedback is weaker than I’d like, but there’s still enough feedback coming through to let you correct slides and push to the limit of what your car can do.</p>



<p>And that’s when the game is at its very best. The handling lets you find those limits and push them constantly. It’s so wonderfully satisfying to hit those zen-like moments where you and the car just seem to be working as one, hitting every apex, nailing every slide and pulling off perfect overtaking moves. Track designs aids in all of this, with almost every course I raced on offering up sweeping bends and fun technical sections. And we’ve already covered how the differing seasons improve things even further by altering the handling. It’s just so, so very bloody good.</p>



<p>The only thing that lets the racing down is the A.I. Once again the horribly named Drivatars are included, the idea being that the A.I. will take on the names of people from your friends list then populate races with them. They’re also meant to replicate the driving style of the people whose names they copy, but frankly I’ve never noticed them doing anything different than the regular A.I. so it’s hard to tell. The point is the virtual opponent’s you race against are not a very fast bunch, nor at they any good at fighting for position as they’ll fail to defend their place, often ignore your existence in favour of following their line and suck at overtaking.</p>



<p>That, however, is one of the few nits that I can pick. While Horizon 4 isn’t a massive leap up from Horizon 3 in any single way the raft of small improvements and additions have resulted in one of the most content packed, fun racing games to ever be released. The new seasons bring some much appreciated extra variety to the mix, the handling is the best its ever been, the selection of cars is superb, there’s freaking heaps to do and it all looks beautiful to boot. If you’re a racing fan you owe it to your happiness and wellbeing to pick this one up. It’s simply brilliant.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Division 2 Review – A Big Improvement</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/25/the-division-2-review-a-big-improvement/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 12:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=94</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/The-Division-2-Cover-Image.jpg?resize=1024%2C538&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44031"/></figure>



<p>It’s pretty crazy that both Anthem and Tom Clancy’s The Division 2 launched in the same month, both offering stacks of loot and lots of shooting. On paper, at least, Anthem sounded like such a cool prospect versus the more grounded reality of The Division 2. Mechanized suits, an alien world, potentially awesome types of loot to hunt down. Yet here we are: Anthem was a disappointment and The Division 2 has wound up improving on the first game in nearly every area. Even with the constraints on loot that a realistic setting imposes the people at Massive have crafted a more interesting loot system than Bioware could manage with their creative freedom. So let’s delve in and review Tom Clancy’s The Division 2.</p>



<h2>The Story, Or Rather The Lack Of</h2>



<p>Considering that Tom Clancy was a prolific and skilled writer known for crafting great stories the original Division didn’t manage to tell a compelling story. I was hoping to see improvement in The Division 2, but sadly the plot here is arguably more forgettable and stingy than the prior game.</p>



<p>So, to recap the basic premise of the franchise: a deadly virus was unleashed on America by infecting money during Black Friday. As one of the Division agents – a group of sleeper agents living among the population who are activated for situations such as this – you head to Washington D.C. and must aid survivors in dealing with the numerous factions who have risen from the ashes. Your ultimate job is to help re-establish the government, using the White House as your base of operations.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-24-20-35-12.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44028"/></figure>



<p>Prior to the launch of The Division 2 a lot was said about Ubisoft shying away from the inherently political themes found within The Division. This is certainly true with Ubisoft placing plenty of politically charged concepts into the game. Hell, in the intro alone the cinematic points out that some people had guns and others did not, and that this played a large role in who survived and who perished.</p>



<p>However, while it does annoy me to see such things brought up but never explored the game’s story problems are much simpler than that. There’s a lack of any interesting or memorable characters. As before your own Division Agent is completely mute, an awkward trope that requires stellar characterization in the rest of the cast to counter which The Division 2 doesn’t manage. I can’t remember a single person’s name.</p>



<p>The story itself is largely drivel, too. It tries to introduce interesting things like rescuing the president but manages to both it at almost every point. There’s nothing of substance, no plot points that grab your attention.</p>



<h2>The Combat Loop, And Why It’s Great</h2>



<p>The big changes come in the form of the enemies you face down. In The Division the various goons you battled where a stupid bunch who made up for their lack of smarts by being able to soak up bullets. This tended to make firefights a chore because you could hunker down and just pop up to shoot the targets, only occasionally moving. However, in The Division 2 the enemy A.I. has gone to college, gotten a few diplomas in How To Kick Agent Arse and deployed onto the battlefield with an urge to prove itself. Enemies are aggressive, will flush you out with grenades and melee attacks and then flank you constantly. As a result you have to always be watching with a keen eye and you need to move smartly to avoid being flanked or pinned down.</p>



<p>The developers intelligently mix the enemies, too, so that you wind up with a heavy gunner and sniper pinning you down while shotgun wielding nutcases move in from both sides. In the first Division you could have still popped your head up, soaked up the bullets and downed a target or two. Here, however, the health system has been reworked so that you’re now quite squishy. It doesn’t take much to blast through the new armor system, which can only be replenished by an armor kit that takes time to apply or a few special skills that also take time. Once your initial armor is gone your health is limited. In other words, if you get pinned down and those shotgun goons are closing in, you’re in a crapload of trouble.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-18-20-3-13.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44021"/></figure>



<p>This all encourages better use of your two chosen skills because in general cooldown times are longer. Clever use of a turret, for example, can help lock down a potential flanking route so that you can feel a little bit safer, while having a drone marking enemy locations is invaluable, especially if playing solo.</p>



<p>As for the enemies the developers have reworked them, too. In the first game they were made harder by simply ramping up the amount of damage they could take. In sci-fi games this works, but in a more realistic setting a human being taking entire magazines worth of bullets was strange. Apparently this was because The Division could only have a small number of A.I. at a time, so health was bumped up to make fights take longer. Now, though, there are a lot of bad guys with standard red health bars who can be put down surprisingly quickly, mixed in with enemies who have chunky armour. The armour is a smart way to explain their ability to soak up damage, but you can focus your fire to break off specific pieces of armor in order to expose the flesh human inside. Skills like the Chem Launcher also let you deal with heavily armoured foes more effectively.</p>



<p>Speaking of which, let me rant about the enemy that consistently caused me to panic; the hammer wielding, armoured lunatics. There’s nothing subtle about these guys, they just charge at you with a freaking sledgehammer and can take you down scarily fast. Their heavy armour often resulting in me freaking the fuck out while running around, because the game loves to pop them into tight environments with a few regular enemies for good measure. Imagine desperately jogging around trying to evade regular bullets while some lunatic with a sledgehammer tries to turn your skull into a jelly dessert.</p>



<p>What I’m ultimately getting at is that while combat in the first Division felt rote and often like a chore, every fight in The Division 2 was thrilling, fun and challenging. I’d usually run into combat in the first game without a thought, knowing I’d blast through it easily. But in The Division I went in knowing that I could get killed quite easily and that it was going to be a genuine challenge.</p>



<h2>Mission Design, And How To Make It Pretty</h2>



<p>It’s a good thing that the combat has been so vastly improved because the basic mission structure in The Division 2 has been left largely untouched. You waltz in and proceed through numerous arenas, gunning down everything in your path before it usually culminates in a named enemy.</p>



<p>But the developers have seemingly realized that while the looter-shooter genre basically boils down to doing the same thing over and over in the name of shiny loot, the way to handle it is to disguise that loop. To that end, mission locations are more varied and interesting. One fight takes place inside a planetarium while images of Earth and space are being projected onto the walls. Another one has you shooting away in a Vietnam war recreation. You’ll get to visit museums and various Washington D.C. landmarks, all of which serve to help hide the fact that you’re just doing fight after fight. It’s like sticking a dress and lipstick on a pig. I mean, yeah, sure, it’s still a pig, but at least it’s a&nbsp;<em>pretty</em>&nbsp;pig, amiright? Anyone? No? Okay, then.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-19-0-21-2.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44022"/></figure>



<h2>Improved Open World</h2>



<p>The original Division’s world was an atmospheric place to explore, a ruined version of New York covered in a dusting of snow. For the Division 2 the setting has shifted over to Washington D.C. and the snow has vanished in favour of a brighter colors and a dynamic weather system. At first the more eeiry atmosphere of the first game seems like it might have vanished, but in reality it hasn’t. There’s still a sense of loneliness as you explore the abandoned streets, but now there’s also a little more life to be found in roving civilian patrols and the occasional settlement where people are trying to make a life.</p>



<p>The new weather system is a superb addition. There are times when a thick fog will settle on the streets, obscuring your vision and turning firefights into a much more tense affair since you rely on sound to pinpoint the baddies. Other times a storm can roll in, the echoing boom of thunder and the downpour of heavy rain making a fight feel dramatic.</p>



<p>One of the things that I didn’t enjoy in The Division was how exploration often felt pointless. There was a vast city that looked beautiful and detailed, yet there wasn’t much reason to venture off the main streets while you moved from one mission to another. For the sequel it seems Massive knew this time and now there are loot boxes to be found everywhere, as well as a few special side-missions and even some unique boss characters waiting to be found.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-16-0-51-45.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44020"/></figure>



<p>Now as you explore the streets random activities will pop up, things like rescuing some hostages or disabling a propaganda broadcast. The XP and loot rewards for doing these things has been bumped up a lot since the first game, ensuring that taking the time to tackle them feels worthwhile.</p>



<p>Everything feeds into the few Settlements strewn around the map and their associated Projects. Completing a project usually requires that you donate some gear, complete activities around the map or perhaps collect SHD Caches that have been sprinkled around Washington D.C. Your hard work is rewarded with big chunks of XP, new bounty opportunities and crafting recipes so that you can mod your weapons and armour. It’s a solid economy that helps you feel like you’re always making progressing, always getting new stuff, always levelling up.</p>



<h2>But What About The Loot?</h2>



<p>By comparison The Division 2 rains down loot like its afraid you won’t love it any more if it doesn’t give you lots of shiny, shiny toys. New chest pieces, knee guards, assault rifles, shotguns and mods are dished out at a fast pace. Perhaps it’s because the realistic setting of The Division means even its exotic gear is still pretty tame, so to make up for that the game just gives you loads and loads of stuff.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-27-20-58-13.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44030"/></figure>



<p>There’s certainly plenty of room for focusing your Agent’s build, even if some of the new stat changes take some getting used to. Skill Power, for example, doesn’t actually increase the effectiveness of your chosens skills, rather you just need a have enough Skill Power to equip certain skill mods.</p>



<p>Speaking of mods they’ve been changed slightly, too. In The Division you could slap a new scope, suppressor and grip onto your favorite assault rifle and they would all provide stat boosts. Now, though, each and every modification offers positive and negative boosts, thus a certain scope might improve accuracy by 20% but drop the damage you do to elite enemies by 15%. It’s an interesting change and one that I personally like as it makes modifying weapons a more thoughtful experience.</p>



<h2>The Endgame Review<br></h2>



<p>The end game is where we’ve seen The Division, Destiny and lately Anthem fail to deliver. Everything leading up to the endgame has often felt lacking, and then once you get through the story there’s been…nothing. Instead we’ve had promises of things being better in the future, a nebulous promise at best. Companies seem more intent on ever than selling customers on roadmaps rather than the game at hand.</p>



<p>So I’m quite pleased to say that The Division 2 offers up a robust and fun endgame. Once you hit the level 30-cap and finish up the campaign missions an ominous cutscene plays that shows a new faction named the Black Tusk invading D.C. These guys are a former paramilitary group packing technology to rival your own as well as stompy robots and a variety of new tricks. They immediately reset your map, which is actually rather saddening since all the work you put in capturing control points and freeing D.C. essentially gets wiped out.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-24-13-44-54.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44026"/></figure>



<p>Once you hit the end game the levelling system you’ve been adhering to is ditched in favor of gear being given a Power rating. Your new goal is to boost this rating until it gets high enough to let you tackle one of the Black Tusk Strongholds, although first you need to complete Invaded missions which are the campaign missions with a Black Tusk twist thrown in for good measure.</p>



<p>In some ways it’s a lazy system since it does re-use all the existing missions, strongholds and Control Points, but the Black Tusk offer enough of a new combat experience to keep things feeling fun. They are aggressive, bring new tricks to fights and offer up new enemy types such as attack dogs.</p>



<p>You also unlock Specialization options, three unique classes that offer a signature weapon and a new skill tree. The survivalist, for example, nets you a grenade launcher, while another Specialization gives you a crossbow. You’re free to swap between Specializations whenever you feel like it, so you can have some fun experimenting.</p>



<p>Control Points become a larger point of contention as enemy factions will battle for control of them, fighting each other and you. It make fast travelling around the map harder, but taking back a Control Point lets you access the supply room again for a pile of loot. Normally, a Control Point’s supply room will restock every 24hrs to give you a constant supply of loot, but factions retaking Control Points sort of speeds things up.</p>



<p>Once you power through the missions and your first Stronghold your World Tier level will increase, making enemies harder and gear more powerful. You do the cycle again, completing two missions and a different stronghold to increase yourself to World Tier 3. Then you do it one last time until you reach World Tier 4. At which you’ve done most of the major content, but a fourth stronghold remains locked, a tantalizing glimpse at your next objective whenever Ubisoft opens the gate. At this final World Tier you’re free to kick back and tackle strongholds, do activities, fight for control points and soak up loot. Raids and new content are all promised for the future with everything apparently going to be free to all players.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-26-20-4-41.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44029"/></figure>



<p>Along with the main campaign which took me about 25-hours to get through the end game feels substantial enough to keep me playing for a while yet. Other smaller things such as a new NPC that appears offering up tricky bounty targets which in turn unlock a special vendor help keep me interested, as do the weekly and daily challenges.</p>



<h2>The Dodgy Dark Zone</h2>



<p>The Dark Zone was arguably the most divisive feature of The Division, a portion of the map where players could turn on other players if they choose while also still fighting the A.I. It was a fascinating idea on paper, but in practice it never did manage to sort itself out as players with high level gear would make mincemeat out of newer players. The first big change combats this, because now when you head into the Dark Zone your gear stats get normalized, putting you on relatively even footing with other players. With a proper fighting chance stepping foot into the Dark Zone should be viable for new players.</p>



<p>There is a single area, though, where stats don’t get normalized so anybody who spends the time required to obtain higher loot will be able to obliterate players who have lower tier gear. This area is referred to as being Invaded, a chunk of Dark Zone where the Black Tusk hang out and all players are classified as Rogue, meaning they can engage each other without penalty.</p>



<p>Speaking of going rogue the temptation to gun down a fellow Divison agent is always present, especially as you watch them hook up their valuable loot to a chopper for extraction. The rogue system has been expanded so that it’s now possible to go rogue by hacking into certain loot containers. Like before, though, turning your back on the Division means other players can gun you down freely, thus to survive you can either hold out until a timer hits zero or you can attempt to find the Thieves Den by performing certain activities around the city. Find the den and you get a nice hunk of XP for your troubles, plus some bonus loot.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-23-14-22-50.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44025"/></figure>



<p>The Dark Zone remains a wonderfully tense place to hang out. There’s now normal loot that you can pick up and keep, so even if you get gunned down at least you’ll typically have something to show for it. But as always the star of the show is the contaminated loot which must be extracted via helicopter, which in turn alerts everybody that a player is trying to get some tasty loot out of the Dark Zone. The wait for the helicopter to arrive feels like an eternity, and the terror you feel as a solo player when a few other Agents come sauntering by is immense.</p>



<p>The Dark Zone can still be a place of friendships, too. Just as much as I ran into squads hunting for lone wolves like myself or smaller groups I also encountered friendly agents who tagged along on my excursions. Sometimes we chatted, sometimes entire partnerships were formed without a single spoken word, just a couple of emotes like waving and jumping jacks. At times the Dark Zone can be infuriating, and at others its capable of producing fantastic stories.</p>



<h2>Some Technical Hiccups</h2>



<p>The Division’s launch a few years back did not exactly go smoothly, so I’m glad to report that The Division 2 is certainly a more polished product out of the (digital) box. With that said there are still issues to be found. Personally I experienced numerous crashes back to desktop, frequently making me lose considerable progress in Strongholds or longer missions.</p>



<p>Connection problems also hampered a lot of my time with the game. Some were simply due to poor Internet on my end, but there were also a lot of times when it seemed to be on the game’s end, especially when it came to grouping up with other players – they’d often just lose connection and vanish.</p>



<p>As smart and satisfying as the A.I. can be to battle against they’re also capable of performing some truly stupid acts. They’ll run madly across a big open space, then proceed to charge back again while you rain down bullets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-24-13-55-12.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44027"/></figure>



<p>I also ran across a couple of examples of things failing to trigger during missions. Luckily they were relatively easy to fix as going backwards through the level and then moving forward again usually resulted in things triggering properly.</p>



<p>I have no doubt that there’s a variety of other problems to be found since its a huge game. But the developers seem to be working quickly to fix what needs to be fixed before moving onto balance changes and future content.</p>



<h2>Closing Thoughts</h2>



<p>Frustratingly we live in a world where a game needs to be praised for feeling complete and satisfying on launch. Yet here we are: The Division 2 actually feels like a whole package capable of providing hours and hours of fun straight out of the box. The promise of more content to come only sweetens the deal.</p>



<p>But let’s talk about the important stuff, shall we? The Division 2 feels like what the original game should have been. It’s a good sequel, taking almost everything about The Division and improving on it. The core loops of fighting and looting feels superb, while the open world has been fleshed out with more interesting activities and a sense of dynamism that was missing from The Division.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Tom-Clancys-The-Division%C2%AE-22019-3-19-17-22-19.jpg?resize=1024%2C429&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44023"/></figure>



<p>It’s just a shame that The Division 2 doesn’t have a strong story to support it. It’s baffling to me that with games like Far Cry 5 and The Division being built on intriguing political and ethical foundations that Ubisoft then seems so intent on claiming that their games are free of politics.</p>



<p>Still, what we’ve gotten is a robust looter-shooter that feels like it runs rings around Anthem’s slim end game and miserly loot. It’s still a looter-shooter at its core and thus the trappings of the genre are present, so if the idea of doing the same things over and over in the name of better loot doesn’t appeal to you then The Division 2 simply won’t change your mind. If piles of shiny new gear haunt your every waking moment, though, then The Division 2 is arguably the best looter-shooter since Borderlands 2 introduced the idea of a diamond pony called Butt Stallion.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wizards: Enhanced Edition Review – Amateur Magician</title>
		<link>./../2019/04/25/the-wizards-enhanced-edition-review-amateur-magician/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 12:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gamesblog.club]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamesblog.club/?p=91</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[
						]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
				
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Wizards-Enhanced-Edition-3dRudder-PSVR-blog-.jpg?resize=1024%2C426&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44119"/></figure>



<p>On paper, I think hurling magic fireballs and casting spells is a near perfect match for the wonders of VR gaming. Who doesn’t want to wave their hands in a vaguely mystical fashion to summon an ice bow? The Wizards attempts to capture the mystic arts by making you swing your hands around like you’re trying to swat a wasp that has no concept of personal space. To the outside world you look like a raving lunatic, but in The Wizards: Enhanced Edition you’re wielding powerful forces.</p>



<p>The Wizards places you into the shoes of a mute wizard who has somehow got caught up with helping out the disembodied voice of another wizard that managed to get himself stuck in a different dimension. There’s not a lot of interesting plot to be found, largely because there are no other characters outside of the disembodied voice, but there is a nice undercurrent of humour.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/TheWizards01.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44115"/></figure>



<p>When you fire up the game you’re given the choice between regular movement, teleportation or a mixture of the two. The choice is actually pointless, though, because you can always teleport regardless of what you choose. The levels make it a requirement to zip around, and the nature of the combat where enemies charge directly at you makes teleporting very handy indeed. Sadly there is no smooth turn option included, so you have to put up with turning by degrees. The VR options on offer are slim, but they do the job.</p>



<p>What would a game about Wizards be without some magic, right? Conjuring up a spell is as simple as holding the trigger/s on your Move controllers and making the appropriate gesture, and I don’t mean the middle finger.</p>



<p>The most basic spell and the very first one that you get access to is the fireball. With a simple flick of your wrist you can summon up a burning orb of pain and hurl it at enemies. Throwing stuff precisely in VR has long been a bit of a tricky problem so a generous aim-assist that lets you somewhat consistently hit the small selection of goblins and trolls. It’s not perfect, certainly, so you’ll see a lot of your fireballs hurtling off in completely the wrong direction.</p>



<p>The next spell is summoning up a shield with a simple wave of your off-hand. You can use this to batter projectiles away or fend of melee attacks, and an upgrade even lets the shield deflect ranged attacks right back at the attacker. Best of the shield can be used in conjunction with fireballs. Quite honestly, walking into a fight and summoning a shield and fireball makes you feel like a certified badass. And trust me the shield is important because the Move controllers ironically make it a bit tricky to move around while casting spells. The lack of analogue sticks continues to be a problem for PS VR in instances like this, and I couldn’t help but wish I was playing on my Oculus Rift.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/TheWizards02.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44116"/></figure>



<p>As you move through the game you’ll get some new spells to play around with that need both hands to use. The ice-bow, for example, feels pretty cool (HA!) to use and allows for some precision aiming at range. You also get the ability to fire electricity from your hands like the freaking Emperor from Star Wars, or you can summon up a bunch of little diamonds that will seek out enemies. The variety of spells on offer wouldn’t exactly make for a thick spell book, but you can buy some upgrades along the way using points. In total, you’ll get a meagre six spells to play around with, all of them handed to you within the first hour of gameplay.</p>



<p>The less than perfect tracking of PS VR does present a couple of problems, though. I’ve got my camera set up at a decent height and the tracking is typically consistent, however in Wizards a few of the spells seem to give the camera some problems. Even the simple flick of the hand to summon a fireball would frequently fail to register correctly. The key seems to be keeping your movements slow so the shape your tracing can be registered.</p>



<p>For the first half of the game the tracking is stronger, simply because there’s less to deal with on-screen. A few enemies will appear at a time, during combat sections where you get locked in until everything is dead, giving you some room to be precise with your movements and nail whichever spell you want. Later, though, there are more baddies on the screen and so your actions become more frantic, which is where the PS VR system seems to struggle.</p>



<p>As a direct result of the sometimes wonky tracking it becomes worryingly easy to rely on the shield and fireball spells over anything else. In the midst of a fight with goblins charging at you and a few trolls edging closer it can be infuriating to go for a more complex, powerful spell only for the tracking to fail. Even without the tracking problems, though, the more powerful spells simply require a lot more time to use properly and in the middle of a bunch of goblins trying to cave your skull in time is a luxury.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/TheWizards03.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44117"/></figure>



<p>I think the other issue here is that The Wizards doesn’t have the presentation values to really sell the wizarding fantasy. Your fireballs look more like glossy orange orbs and the impact of the magic lacks oomph. Even with some upgrades that allow you to set enemies on fire or to arc lighting from one baddie to another the visceral feeling it needs is missing. However, due to the budget nature of the game these drawbacks are understandable and forgivable.</p>



<p>The environments are more of a mixed bag of quality. A fantasy world is ripe for amazing vistas that use the power of VR to immerse the player and make them want to explore every inch of it. But The Wizards often has bleak, lifeless environments that are only occasionally spiced up, such as when you get to see a dragon land on a tower above you. It’s one of the very few moments where I stopped to soak The Wizards world in. A little too much time is spent in bog-standard caves, tunnels or rooms, none of which help to make the game’s world more interesting.</p>



<p>Tight money restraints make themselves felt in the lack of detailed textures, clunky animations and limited enemy designs, too.<br></p>



<p>This is all sounding rather negative, so let’s balance that out because The Wizards can still be a lot of fun at times. There’s a wonderful tactile sense to the gestures required to use spells, which is funny since you are just waving your hands in the air. While I do wish there was more variety in the available spells – especially since you get them all quite quickly, leaving nothing new for the rest of The Wizards – the ones that you do get are fun to use. My personal favourite were the shards which automatically seek out enemies. When summoned they float in the air in front of you, and to send a shard out you have to touch it. An upgrade will turn certain shards red which causes them to do more damage. Each time you tap a red shard another shard changes from blue to red, so if you do them in sequence you can unleash a barrage of deadly projectiles that murder anything in the area.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/wolfsgamingblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/TheWizards04.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-44118"/></figure>



<p>There’s a good sense of scale in the game, too. The many trolls you fight become repetitive, sure, but they also tower over you and thus when they swing their clubs it feels threatening. The shining example of this are the rare but fun boss fights where the bad guys is quite simply bloody massive. Use of scale like this is something I love in VR because it really does help put you into the game.</p>



<p>Some light puzzles elements help to break up the otherwise predictable action. The Wizards began life as a standard wave-shooter with the player rooted in place, but free movement and exploration got added later in development. That wave-shooter design is still strong, though, as combat areas are obvious, you get sealed into them until everything is defeated and the enemies tend to spawn from obvious spots. The occasional puzzles provide some welcome change, even if they don’t tax the mind very much. One section, for example, involves opening doors by standing on coloured switches.</p>



<p>The Wizards: Enhanced Edition takes somewhere in the region of three hours to complete. The leaderboards and difficulty modifying cards you can find make it clear that the game is meant to be about chasing the highest scores. Sadly that’s not for me as the gameplay doesn’t have the depth I look for when chasing high scores. Because I didn’t feel the urge to replay levels the repetitive nature of the gameplay was a difficult thing to forgive when the whole experience is only three hours long.</p>



<p>You get an arena mode as well where you unsurprisingly just battle against waves and waves of enemies, the ultimate goal being to simply survive as long as you can. Personally, I played a few rounds and then dropped out of the Arena. On its own the spell-based combat in The Wizards: Enhanced Edition doesn’t offer enough flexibility or depth to support nothing but constant fighting.</p>



<p>Ultimately The Wizards doesn’t quite manage to nail the whole wizarding thing as much as I’d have liked. The small spell selection and repetitive gameplay left me feeling uninterested after an hour or two of playing. However, it does make for a nice, casual VR game, especially if you’ve always longed to be the next Gandalf.</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
